（M级行星 尼比卢）
Damn it，man！That was our ride！
有没搞错 这是我们的坐骑
You just stunned our ride！
你把我们的坐骑给击晕了
Oh，great.
这下可好了
Run！
快跑
What the hell did you take？
你到底拿走了什么东西
I have no idea，but they were bowing to it.
我不知道 但那些人对着它鞠躬来着
Kirk to Shuttle One.
柯克呼叫一号穿梭机
Locals are out of the kill zone.
当地人已经离开危险区域
You are clear。Repeat.
可以行动 重复
Spock，get in there，
斯波克 快进去
neutralize the volcano and let's get out of here.
把火山停息下来然后一起离开这里
We have to do this now！I told the Captain
现在就要行动了 我跟舰长说了
the shuttle wasn't built for this kind of heat.
这穿梭机承受不了这样的高温
Captain，did the indigenous life forms see you？
舰长 那些土著有没有看到你
No，Mr。Spock，they did not.
没有 斯波克先生 他们没看到
The Prime Directive clearly states
最高指导原则明确规定
there can be no interference
不得干涉
with the internal development of alien civilizations.
外星文明的内部发展
I know what it says！Which is why I'm running
我知道这个规定 所以我才
through the jungle wearing a disguise！
穿着伪装在丛林里狂奔
Now drop off your super ice cube and let's go！
快把你的超级冰块扔下去然后走人
Kirk out！
柯克通话完毕
You're good.
准备好了
If we're gonna do this，we've got to do it now！
现在不行动就没机会了
This ash is killing our coils.
火山灰正在损坏我们的线圈
You sure you don't want me to go instead？
你确定你不要我替你下去吗
That would be highly illogical as I am already outfitted…
这想法极不合逻辑 因为我已着装完毕
Spock，I was kidding.
斯波克 我开玩笑的
You got this.
你能行的
Guys！We have to go！Now！
伙计们 要出发了 快啊
They're trying to kill us！
他们想杀掉我们
They're trying to kill us，Jim！
他们想杀掉我们 吉姆
I'll see you in 90 seconds.
我们90秒后见
Do it，do it！
快点 快点
Prerequisite change，2-7-3…
先决条件改变 2-7-3
（引擎过热）
I can't hold this position.
我无法稳住飞船了
Spock，I've got to pull you back up.
斯波克 我得把你拉回来
Negative。This is our only chance to save this species.
不行 这是拯救这个物种的唯一机会
If this volcano erupts，the planet dies.
如果火山爆发 这星球就完了
Pull him back up。Now！
把他拉上来 马上
Spock，are you okay？
斯波克 你还好吗
I am，
我
surprisingly，alive。Stand by.
竟然还活着 待命
We have to get him back.
我们得把他弄回来
I'll suit up。I'm gonna go down.
我去换装备 我要下去
We have to abandon the shuttle.
我们要弃船了
We can't just leave him，Sulu！
我们不能丢下他 苏鲁
We don't have a choice！
我们别无选择
Uhura，I'm sorry.
乌胡拉 很抱歉
Spock，we're going back to the Enterprise.
斯波克 我们现在要回进取号
We'll get you out of there.
我们会把你救出来的
Captain，I'm ditching the shuttle.
舰长 我要弃船了
You've got to make it to the Enterprise on your own.
你要自己想办法回进取号
Wonderful！
太「好」了
Uhura！You ready to swim？
乌胡拉 准备好游泳了吗
I'm ready.
准备好了
Jim！
吉姆
Jim！The beach is that way！
吉姆 海滩在那边
I know！We're not going to the beach！
我知道 我们不去海滩
Oh，no，no，no！
不不不
I hate this！
我讨厌这样
I know you do！
我知道
Do you have any idea how ridiculous it is
你知道把一艘星舰藏在海底
to hide a starship on the bottom of the ocean？
是多么荒唐的事吗
We've been down here since last night！
从昨晚开始我们就待在这里了
The salt water's gonna ruin the…
海水会破坏掉…
Scotty！Where's Spock？
小科 斯波克在哪里
Still in the volcano，sir.
还在火山里 长官
Captain on the bridge！
舰长到达舰桥
Lieutenant，do we have an open channel to Mr。Spock？
上尉 能联系上斯波克先生吗
The heat's frying his comms，
高温正在损坏他的通讯设备
but we still have contact.
但还能联系上
Spock？
斯波克
I have activated the device，Captain.
我已经将装置启动 舰长
When the countdown is complete，
倒数计时结束后
the reaction should render the volcano inert.
火山的喷发应该能被阻止
Yeah，and that's gonna render him inert！
是的 同时他也会没命
Do we have use of the transporters？
我们能用传送装置吗
- Negative，sir。- Not with these magnetic fields.
- 不行 长官 - 这里的磁场太强
I need to beam Spock back to the ship.
我要把斯波克传送回来
Give me one way to do it.
给我想个办法
Maybe if we had a direct line of sight.
如果我们能直接看到
- If we got closer… - Hold on，wee man！
- 如果我们靠近点 - 等等 小家伙
You're talking about an active volcano！
那可是座活火山
Sir，if that thing erupts，
长官 如果那东西喷发了
I cannae guarantee we can withstand the heat！
我无法保证我们能承受住那种高温
I don't know that we can maintain that kind of altitude.
我不知道我们是否能维持在那种高度上
Our shuttle was concealed by the ash cloud，
穿梭机能藏在灰云里
but the Enterprise is too large.
但是进取号太大了
If utilized in a rescue effort，
如果用它进行营救任务
it would be revealed to the indigenous species.
那些土著就会发现它
Spock，nobody knows the rules better than you，
斯波克 没有人比你更清楚那些规定
but there has got to be an exception.
但是总有破例的时候
None。Such action violates the Prime Directive.
不行 这种行为会违反最高指导原则
Shut up，Spock！
闭嘴 斯波克
We're trying to save you，damn it！
我们在想办法救你 该死的
Doctor，the needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few.
医生 多数人之需重于少数人之求
Spock，we're talking about your life！
斯波克 这可是你的性命啊
The rule cannot be broken…
人可死 规矩不可破
Spock！
斯波克
Try to get him back online.
想办法重新联系上他
Ninety seconds to detonations.
离爆炸还有90秒
If Spock were here and I were there，what would he do？
如果我和斯波克互换了位置 他会怎么做
He'd let you die.
他会让你死
Spock！
斯波克
You all right？
你没事吧
Captain，you let them see our ship.
舰长 你让他们看到了我们的星舰
He's fine.
他没事
Bridge to Captain Kirk.
舰桥呼叫柯克舰长
Yes，Lieutenant.
请讲 上尉
Is Commander Spock on board，sir？
中校斯波克在船上了吗 长官
Safely and soundly.
毫发无伤
Please notify him that his device
请告诉他 他的装置
has successfully detonated.
已成功引爆
You hear that？Congratulations，Spock.
听到了吗 恭喜你 斯波克
You just saved the world.
你拯救了这个世界
You violated the Prime Directive.
你违反了最高指导原则
Oh，come on，Spock.
别这样 斯波克
They saw us。Big deal.
不就是被他们看到了吗
《星际迷航：暗黑无界》
（伦敦 2259年55日）
（皇家儿童医院）
I can save her.
我能救她
What did you say？
你说什么
Your daughter.
你的女儿
I can save her.
我能救她
Who are you？
你是谁
Oh，Jim。Come on，let it go.
吉姆 别管它
Jim！
吉姆
You're not actually gonna answer that，are you？
你真的要接那电话吗
（旧金山星际舰队总部）
Spock，I'm telling you，
斯波克 我告诉你
this is why he called。I can feel it.
他打电话就是为了这事 我有预感
Your feeling aside，I consider it highly unlikely
不管你的预感 我觉得我们
that we will be selected for the new program.
入选这次新项目的可能性极小
Why else would Pike want to see us？
那派克为什么要见我们
Forget about seniority.
抛开资历不说
They gave us the newest ship in the fleet.
他们给了我们舰队里最新的星舰
I mean，who else are they gonna send out？
他们还能派谁去
I can think of numerous possibilities.
我能想到很多种可能性
A five- year mission，Spock！
五年的任务 斯波克
That's deep space！That's uncharted territory！
那可是深空 无人踏足过的领域
Think how incredible that's gonna be.
想想那有多酷啊
Hey，ladies。Jim Kirk.
美女们 我是吉姆·柯克
- 「Uneventful.」 - Admiral？
- 「无事发生」 - 上将
It's the way you described
你在舰长日志里
the survey of Nibiru in your captain's log.
是这么描述尼比卢勘测任务的
Yes，sir，I didn't want
是的 长官 我不想
to waste your time going over the details.
让您浪费时间过目那些细节
Tell me more about this volcano.
再给我说说这火山
Data says it was highly volatile.
数据表明它极度不稳定
If it were to erupt，it would wipe out the planet.
如果爆发了 就会毁掉整个星球
Let's hope it doesn't，sir.
希望它不会爆发 长官
Something tells me it won't.
直觉告诉我它不会爆发
Well，sir，volatile is all relative.
长官 不稳定都是相对的
Maybe our data was off.
也许我们的数据有误
Or maybe it didn't erupt
或者 它没爆发的原因
because Mr。Spock detonated
也许是因为斯波克先生
a cold fusion device inside it
在里面引爆了一枚冷凝弹
right after a civilization that's barely invented the wheel
你们还让一个连轮子都没发明出来的文明
happened to see a starship rising out of their ocean！
目睹了一艘星舰在海洋里升起
That is pretty much how you describe it，is it not？
你就是这么描述的 对吧
- Admiral… - You filed a report？
- 上将 - 你在报告里说了这事？
Why didn't you tell me？
你怎么不告诉我
I incorrectly assumed that
我错误地认为
you would be truthful in your captain's log.
你会在舰长日志里如实描述
Yeah，I would have been if I didn't have to save your life.
如果不是为了救你我也不会隐瞒
A fact for which I am immeasurably grateful
对此我非常感激
and the very reason I felt it necessary
同时这也正是我觉得有必要
to take responsibility for the actions…
为这个行为承担责任的原因
Take responsibility，yeah.
负责任 说得好
That'd be so noble，pointy，
你真够高尚的 尖耳朵
if you weren't also throwing me under the bus.
如果你没有恩将仇报的话
「Pointy」？Is that a derogatory reference to…
「尖耳朵」 你这是在贬低…
Gentlemen.
先生们
Starfleet's mandate is to explore and observe，not to interfere.
舰队的任务是探索和观察 而不是干涉
Had the mission gone according to plan，Admiral，
如果那次任务能按计划进行 上将
the indigenous species would never
那些土著绝对不会
have been aware of our interference.
察觉到我们的干涉
That's a technicality.
前提是计划能完美执行
I am Vulcan，sir。We embrace technicality.
我是瓦肯人 长官 我们追求完美
Are you giving me attitude，Spock？
你就这种态度吗 斯波克
I'm expressing multiple attitudes simultaneously，sir.
我在同时表达多种态度 长官
To which are you referring？
您指的是哪种
Out.
出去
You're dismissed，Commander.
你可以走了 中校
You have any idea what a pain in the ass you are？
你知不知道你有多让人头疼
I think so，sir.
我知道 长官
So tell me what you did wrong.
告诉我你做错了什么
What's the lesson to be learned here？
学到了什么教训
Never trust a Vulcan.
永远不要相信瓦肯人
Now，see，you can't even answer the question.
你甚至不好好回答问题
You lied。On an official report，you lied.
你撒谎了 在官方文件里撒谎了
You think the rules don't apply to you
你以为你不赞成那些规章制度
'cause you disagree with them.
就能不受它们的约束
That's why you talked me into signing up in the first place.
您当初要我加入正是因为我不守规矩
It's why you gave me your ship.
这也是为什么您给了我您的船
I gave you my ship because I saw a greatness in you.
我把船给你是因为我之前觉得你会成大器
And now，I see you haven't got an ounce of humility.
而现在 我却发现你毫无谦逊之心
What was I supposed to do，let Spock die？
那我该怎么办 让斯波克死吗
You're missing the point.
你没听懂我的意思
I don't think I am，sir。What would you have done？
我懂 长官 是你你会怎么做
I wouldn't have risked my First Officer's life
我根本就不会拿我的大副的
in the first place！
性命去冒险
You were supposed to survey a planet，
你们本该去调查一个星球
not alter its destiny！
而不是改变它的命运
You violated a dozen Starfleet regulations
你违反了一堆舰队规定
and almost got everyone under your command killed.
还几乎让你的手下全部丧命
Except I didn't！
但是他们没死
You know how many crew members I've lost？Not one！
你知道我损失过多少船员吗 一个也没
That's your problem，you think you're infallible！
这就是你的问题 你觉得你很完美
You think you can't make a mistake.
你觉得你不会犯错
It's a pattern with you！
你一向都是这样
- The rules are for other people！- Some should be.
- 以为规定是给别人看的 - 有些应该是
And what's worse is you using blind luck
更糟的是 你仗着自己运气好
to justify your playing God！
就以为自己是上帝
Given the circumstances，
这次事关重大
this has been brought to Admiral Marcus's attention.
已经引起了马科斯上将的注意
He convened a special tribunal，to which I was not invited.
他召集了一次特别法庭 但没有邀请我
You understand what Starfleet regulations mandate
你自己明白 按舰队的规定
be done at this point.
你会受到怎样的处罚
They've taken the Enterprise away from you.
他们已经收回了进取号
They're sending you back to the Academy.
还要把你送回学院
Admiral，listen…
上将 听我说
- No，I'm not going to listen。- I can justify…
- 不 我不听 - 我可以解释
Why should I listen？I'm not going to listen.
我为什么要听 我不听
You don't listen to anybody but yourself！
你只听自己的
I understand regulation，but every decision I've made…
我明白那些规定 但我所做的每个决定
No！I can't listen！
不 我不能听
You don't comply with the rules，
你不服从规定
you don't take responsibility for anything，
不为任何事情负责任
and you don't respect the chair.
还不拿舰长这位置当回事
You know why？
知道为什么吗
Because you're not ready for it.
因为你还没有准备好
（伦敦）
（开尔文纪念档案馆）
I'm going to need three titanium…
我要三个钛
Radiation protection is required in this area.
进入此区域前请做好防辐射措施
（传送完毕）
How did you find me？
你是怎么找到我的
I know you better than you think I do.
我比你想像中更了解你
The first time I found you was in a dive like this.
我第一次看到你就是在这种破酒吧
Remember that？You got your ass handed to you.
记得吗 你被人打得满地找牙
No，I didn't.
才没有
- You don't？- No，that's not what happened.
- 没有吗 - 没有 事实不是那样
- That was an epic beating。- No，it wasn't.
- 你被揍了个半死 - 不是
You had napkins hanging out of your nose.
你的鼻孔里插了一大坨纸巾
Did you not？
没有吗
Yeah，that was a good fight.
那次打得真爽
「A good fight.」
「打得真爽」
I think that's your problem right there.
我想这就是你的问题所在
They gave her back to me.
他们把她还给了我
The Enterprise.
进取号
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Watch your back with that First Officer，though.
多提防那位大副
Spock's not going to be working with me.
斯波克不会当我的大副
He's been transferred.
他被调职了
U.S.S。Bradbury.
调去了联邦星舰布拉德伯里号
You're going to be my First Officer.
你来当我的大副
Yeah，Marcus took some convincing.
马科斯是个很难说服的人
But every now and then I can make a good case.
但我偶尔也能说动他
What did you tell him？
你跟他怎么说的
The truth.
我说了实话
That I believe in you.
我说我相信你
That if anybody deserves a second chance，
如果有人有资格改过自新
it's Jim Kirk.
那这个人只能是吉姆·柯克
I don't know what to say.
我不知道该说什么
That is a first.
这还是头一次
It's going to be okay，son.
会没事的 孩子
「Emergency session，Daystrom.」
「紧急会议 地点戴斯图姆」
That's us.
你也得去
Yeah.
知道了
Suit up.
去穿上制服
All Starfleet personnel，please be advised，
所有星际舰队人员请注意
- new security protocols are in effect。- Captain.
- 新安全规定已生效 - 舰长
Not anymore，Spock。First Officer.
已经不是了 斯波克 现在是大副
I was demoted and you were reassigned.
我被降级了 而你被调职了
It is fortunate that the consequences
很幸运后果没有
were not more severe.
比这个更严重
You've got to be kidding me.
开什么玩笑
Captain，it was never my intention…
舰长 我从没打算要…
Not Captain.
我不是舰长
I saved your life，Spock.
我救了你的命 斯波克
You wrote a report，I lost my ship.
然后你写了一份报告 我的星舰就没了
Commander，I see now I should have alerted you
中校 我现在觉得当初应该告诉你
to the fact that I submitted the report.
我交了那份报告
No，I'm familiar with your compulsion to follow the rules.
不 我很清楚你循规蹈矩的强迫症
But you see，I can't do that.
但是我做不到
Where I come from，if someone saves your life，
地球人的规矩是 如果有人救了你一命
you don't stab him in the back.
你就不该暗算他
Vulcans cannot lie.
瓦肯人不能撒谎
Then I'm talking to the half- human part of you.
那我就是在跟你人类的那一半说话
All right？
好吗
Do you understand why I went back for you？
你知不知道我为什么要回去救你
Commander Spock？Frank Abbot，
斯波克中校吗 我是弗兰克·阿伯特
U.S.S。Bradbury.
联邦星舰布拉德伯里号舰长
Guess you're with me.
你是我的手下吧
Yes，Captain.
是的 舰长
The truth is，
是因为
I'm going to miss you.
我会想念你
Admiral Marcus，sir.
马科斯上将 长官
Thank you for convening on such short notice.
感谢大家能在这么短时间内集合
Be seated.
请坐
By now，some of you have heard what happened in London.
你们当中有些人已经听说伦敦的事了
The target was a Starfleet data archive.
被袭击的是星际舰队的一个档案馆
Now it's a damned hole in the ground，
现在那里只剩一个大坑了
42 men and women are dead.
死了42个人
One hour ago，
一个小时前
I received a message from a Starfleet officer，
我收到一位舰队官员的信息
who confessed to carrying out this attack.
他承认这次袭击是他干的
that he was being forced to do it by this man，
有人逼他干的
Commander John Harrison。He's one of our own.
这个人是中校约翰·哈里森 我们的人
And he is the man responsible for this act of savagery.
他是这起恐怖袭击的始作俑者
For reasons unknown，John Harrison has just declared
出于某种未知的原因 约翰·哈里森
a one- man war against Starfleet.
只身向星际舰队宣战了
And under no circumstances are we to allow this man
无论如何 我们都不能让这个人
to escape Federation space.
逃出联邦领空
You here tonight represent the senior command
今晚在座各位涵盖了本星区
of all the vessels in the region.
所有星舰的高级将领
And in the name of those we lost，
为了我们失去的一切
you will run this bastard down.
一定要抓住这畜生
This is a manhunt，pure and simple，so let's get to work.
简而言之 这是一次追捕 动手吧
Earth's perimeter sensors have not detected
地球周边传感器尚未检测出
any warp signatures leaving the system，
有任何曲速迹象离开地球
so we know he can't be far.
所以他还没走远
You will park your ships in a blockade formation
把所有星舰排成封锁队形
then deploy search vehicles and landing parties
派出搜索舰和陆上部队
to run down every lead.
不放过任何一个线索
This man has shown willingness to kill innocent people，
这个人会杀害无辜民众
so the rules of engagement are simple.
所以交战规则很简单
If you come across this man and fear for your life
如果你遇到此人 担心他伤及自己
or the lives of those nearby，
或周围的人的性命
you are authorized to use deadly force on sight.
你有权使用致命武器
- What's in the bag？- James，not now.
- 包里是什么 - 詹姆斯 等等再说
It doesn't seem odd to you that he'd target an archive？
他袭击档案馆 你不觉得奇怪吗
It's like bombing a library.
这就像去炸图书馆
Chris？Everything okay there？
克里斯 有事吗
Yes，sir。Mr。Kirk is just acclimating
没事 长官 柯克先生只是
to his new position as First Officer.
还不太习惯当大副
You got something to say，Kirk，say it.
你如果有话要说 柯克 就说出来吧
Tomorrow's too late.
留到明天就晚了
I'm fine，sir。My apologies.
我没话要说 长官 抱歉
Spit it out，son。Don't be shy.
说吧 孩子 别害羞
Why the archive？
为什么要袭击档案馆
All that information is public record.
那里所有的信息都是公开的
If he really wanted to damage Starfleet，
如果他真想毁灭星际舰队
this could just be the beginning.
这也许只是开始
The beginning of what，Mr。Kirk？
什么的开始 柯克先生
Sir，in the event of an attack，protocol mandates
长官 按照规定 一旦发生袭击
that senior command gather captains and first officers
高级将领必须将所有舰长和大副
at Starfleet H.Q.，right here
召集到星际舰队总部这里
- in this room。- It is curious Harrison
- 这个房间 - 奇怪的是
would commandeer a jumpship without warp capabilities…
哈里森抢了一艘没有曲速飞行能力的飞船
Clear the room！
离开这里
No！
不
We need an air defense team！Daystrom Conference Room！
我们需要防空兵 戴斯图姆会议厅
- Let's go！- Cover me！
- 快走 - 掩护我
- Target acquired。- Take him out！
- 已瞄准目标 - 带他出去
Watch my flank！
留心我侧面
- Go，go，go！- Cover me！
- 走走走 - 掩护我
Fire！
开火
Yeah？
喂
Commander，Mr。Scott has found something
中校 斯科特先生在哈里森的
in the wreckage of Harrison's ship.
飞船残骸里发现了一些东西
He has asked to see us right away.
他说要立刻见我们
Captain！I found this in the crashed jumpship，sir.
舰长 我在飞船里发现了这个
- This is how the bastard got away。- What do you mean？
- 那畜生就是这样逃走的 - 什么意思
It's a portable transwarp beaming device.
这是便携式超曲速传送装置
Well，can you figure out where he went？
你能找出他去哪里了吗
I already did，sir。And you're no gonna like it.
找出了 长官 你不会喜欢那个地方
He's gone to the one place we…
他去了唯一一个
we just can't go.
我们去不了的地方
Admiral，sir，he's not on Earth.
上将 他不在地球
He's on Kronos，sir.
他在克隆那斯 长官
I request my command be reinstated
我请求复职
and your permission to go after him.
并请您允许我去追捕他
Give us a minute.
我们稍后再议
- Kronos。- Yes，sir.
- 克隆那斯 - 是的 长官
So Harrison's gone to the Klingon homeworld.
你是说哈里森去了克林贡人的母星
- Is he defecting？- We're not sure，sir.
- 他叛变了吗 - 不确定 长官
He has taken refuge in the Ketha Province，
他正在凯萨区避难
a region uninhabited for decades.
那里几十年来都没人居住过
He's gotta be hiding there，sir！
他一定藏在那里 长官
He knows if we even go near Klingon space，
他知道如果我们靠近克林贡人的地盘
it'd be all- out war.
就会爆发全面战争
Starfleet can't go after him，but I can.
星际舰队不能去追捕他 但我能
Please，sir.
求您了 长官
All- out war with the Klingons is inevitable，Mr。Kirk.
和克林贡人的全面战争在所难免 柯克先生
If you ask me，it's already begun.
在我看来 战争已经开始了
Since we first learned of their existence，
自从我们知道他们的存在以来
the Klingon Empire has conquered and occupied
克林贡帝国已经侵占了
two planets that we know of
两个我们已知的星球
and fired on our ships half a dozen times.
并数次向我们的星舰开火
They are coming our way.
他们已经磨刀霍霍
London was not an archive.
在伦敦被毁的不是档案馆
It was a top- secret branch of Starfleet
而是星际舰队的绝密分支
designated Section 31.
代号31区
They were developing defense technology
那里的人员负责发展防御技术
and training our officers to gather intelligence
培训我们的军官 用于搜集克林贡人
on the Klingons and any other potential enemy
和任何可能对我们有害的
who means to do us harm.
潜在敌人的情报
Harrison was one of our top agents.
哈里森就是其中一位高级特工
Well，now he's a fugitive and I want to take him out.
现在他是一个逃犯 我要消灭他
Pike always said you were one of our best and brightest.
派克总说你是最好的 也是最有前途的
You should have heard him defend you.
你应该听听他是怎么为你辩护的
He's the one who talked you into joining Starfleet，wasn't he？
是他劝你加入星际舰队的 对吧
Yes，sir.
是的 长官
Did he ever tell you who talked him into joining？
他有没有告诉你是谁劝他加入的
His death is on me.
他的死责任在我
And yours can't be.
我不能再让你去送死
Sir，please。All I…
长官 求您了
Mr。Spock，you said the province
斯波克先生 你说哈里森
where Harrison is hiding is uninhabited？
藏身的地区无人居住
Affirmative，sir.
是的 长官
As part of our defensive strategy，
作为我们防御战略的一部分
31 developed a new photon torpedo.
31区开发了一种新型光子鱼雷
Long- range and untraceable，
远程射击 无迹可寻
it would be invisible to Klingon sensors.
可以避开克林贡人的传感器
I don't want you hurt，but I want to take him out.
我不想你出事 但是我也想消灭他
You park on the edge of the Neutral Zone，
你停在中立区的边缘
you lock onto Harrison's position，
锁定哈里森的位置
you fire，you kill him and you haul ass.
开火 干掉他 立马离开
Permission to reinstate Mr。Spock as my First Officer.
请允许斯波克先生继续做我的大副
Granted.
批准
Jim！
吉姆
- Where were you？- For what？
- 你去哪了 - 干嘛
Your medical exam.
体验
Ten hours ago，you were in a damn firefight.
10个小时前 你刚和敌人交过火
- Now it's my duty as ship's… - I'm fine，Bones.
- 我作为星舰医生 - 我没事 老骨头
The hell you are.
你一点也不像没事
I'm fine.
我没事
Status report，Mr。Spock.
情况如何 斯波克先生
The Enterprise should be ready for launch
进取号在我们到达时
by the time we arrive.
应该可以出发了
- Good。Good。- Captain.
- 很好 很好 - 舰长
Thank you for requesting my reinstatement.
感谢你请求让我复职
You're welcome.
不客气
As I am again your First Officer，it is now my duty
既然我重新成为了你的大副 我有责任
to strongly object to our mission parameters.
强烈反对本次任务的执行方式
Of course it is.
当然
There is no Starfleet regulation
没有哪条星际舰队的规定表明
that condemns a man to die without a trial，
可以不经审判判处一个人死刑
something you and Admiral Marcus are forgetting.
你和马科斯上将都忘了这点
Also，preemptively firing torpedoes
还有 率先向克林贡人的母星
at the Klingon homeworld goes against…
发射鱼雷违反了
You yourself said the area's uninhabited.
你自己也说那地方无人居住
There's only gonna be one casualty.
所以只会有一个人死掉
And in case you weren't listening，
也许你刚才没仔细听
our orders have nothing to do with Starfleet regulation.
我们的任务和星际舰队规定无关
Wait a minute。We're firing torpedoes at the Klingons？
等等 我们要向克林贡人发射鱼雷吗
Regulations aside，this action is morally wrong.
且不谈规定 这种做法也不合道义
Regulations aside，
且不谈规定
pulling your ass out of a volcano was morally right.
把你救离火山很合道义
And I didn't win any points for that.
可我没得到什么好处
Whoa，Jim，calm down.
吉姆 冷静点
I'm not gonna take ethics lessons from a robot！
我不会让一个机器人给我上道德课
Reverting to name- calling suggests that you are defensive
再次开始骂人说明你怀有戒心
and therefore find my opinion valid.
因此 我的意见是正确的
I wasn't asking for your opinion.
我没问你意见
Bones，get that thing off my face.
老骨头 把那东西从我脸上拿开
Captain，our mission could start a war
舰长 我们的任务可能会引发
with the Klingons
和克林贡人的战争
and it is，by its very definition，immoral.
而且十分不合道义
Perhaps you should take the requisite time
或许你该花点时间
to arrive at this conclusion for yourself.
自己得出这个结论
Captain Kirk.
柯克舰长
Science Officer Wallace.
我是科学专员华莱士
I've been assigned to the Enterprise by Admiral Marcus.
受马科斯上将指派来进取号
These are my transfer orders.
这是我的调任令
You requested an additional science officer，Captain？
你有请求增加一名科学专员吗 舰长
I wish I had.
我希望我有
「Lieutenant Carol Wallace.」
卡罗尔·华莱士上尉
「Doctorate in applied physics
应用物理学博士
「Specializing in advanced weaponry.」
擅长领域 先进武器
Impressive credentials.
简历很棒
Thank you.
谢谢
But redundant now that I am back aboard the Enterprise.
既然我回到了进取号 这样就多余了
And yet，the more the merrier.
多多益善
- Have a seat，Doctor。- Thank you.
- 请坐 博士 - 谢谢
Shuttle crew，stand by for lift- off.
穿梭机机组人员 准备升空
No！I'm not signing anything！
不 我什么都不会签的
Now，get these bloody things off my ship！Captain！
把这些该死的东西撤下我的船 舰长
Is there a problem，Mr。Scott？
有问题吗 斯科特先生
Aye，sir。I was just explaining to this gentleman
是的 长官 我正在向这位先生解释
that I cannae authorize any weapons on board this ship
我不能允许这艘星舰搭载任何
without knowing what's inside them.
内部构造未知的武器
Mr。Scott raises yet another point…
斯科特先生的话的意思是
Report to the bridge.
向舰桥报到
Captain.
舰长
Mr。Scott，I understand your concerns，
斯科特先生 我明白你的担忧
but we need these torpedoes on board.
但是我们需要这些鱼雷
Due respect，sir，but photon torpedoes run on fuel.
恕我直言 长官 光子鱼雷需要燃料
Now，I cannae detect the type of fuel
但我检测不出这些鱼雷的
that's in the compartments on these torpedoes
燃料舱里装的是什么燃料
because it's shielded.
因为燃料舱被屏蔽了
Now，I asked for the specifications，but he said…
我问他要规格说明 但他说
- It's classified。- It's classified.
- 这是机密 - 这是机密
So I said，「No specs，no signature！」
所以我说 不给规格说明 不签字
Captain.
舰长
Flight check's complete。We're good to go，sir.
飞行检查完成 随时可以起飞 长官
- Thank you，Mr。Sulu。- Yes，sir.
- 谢谢 苏鲁先生 - 不谢 长官
Now if you'll excuse me，sir，I have a warp core to prime.
恕我失陪 长官 我还要启动曲速核
Get down！
下来
Jim，your vitals are way off.
吉姆 你的身体状况不太好
Report to the med bay。Scotty！
报告给医务舱 小科
I need you to approve those weapons.
我需要你批准这些武器登舰
Do you know what this is，Captain？
你知道这是什么吗 舰长
I don't have time for a lecture，Scotty.
我没空听你演讲 小科
- Do you know what this is？- It's a warp core.
- 你知道这是什么吗 - 这是曲速核
It's a radioactive catastrophe waiting to happen.
是无可避免的放射性灾难
A subtle shift in magnetic output
发射一个或几十个
from，say，firing one or more of six dozen torpedoes
杀伤力未知的鱼雷所造成的磁性输出变化
with an unknown payload
哪怕很小
could set off a chain reaction
都会引发连锁反应
which would kill every living thing on this ship.
杀死这艘星舰上的所有生命
Letting those torpedoes on board the Enterprise
要是让那些鱼雷上进取号
is the last straw！
我就忍无可忍了
- What was the first straw？- What was the…
- 你还有别的东西要忍吗 - 什么
There are plenty of straws.
要忍的东西多的是
How about Starfleet confiscating my transwarp equation？
包括星际舰队没收了我的超曲速方程
And now some madman's using it to hop across the galaxy！
现在有个疯子用它横穿银河系
Where do you think he got it from？
你觉得他是从哪得到的
We have our orders，Scotty！
我们有我们的任务 小科
That's what scares me.
这正是我担心的地方
This is clearly a military operation.
这显然是一次军事行动
Is that what we are now？
这是我们该干的吗
'Cause I thought we were explorers.
我以为我们是负责探索的
Sign for the torpedoes，that's an order.
签署批准鱼雷登舰 这是命令
Right，well，you leave me no choice
好吧 那我别无选择
but to resign my duties.
只能辞职了
Come on，Scotty.
别这样 小科
You're giving me no choice，sir。I will not stand by…
你让我别无选择 长官 我不会同意
You're not giving me much of a choice.
你也没给我什么选择
Will you just make an exception and sign…
你就不能破个例
Do you accept my resignation or not？
你到底批不批准我的辞职
I do！
批准
I do.
我批准
You are relieved，Mr。Scott.
你离职了 斯科特先生
Jim，for the love of God，do not use those torpedoes.
吉姆 看在上帝份上 别用那些鱼雷
Attention。Warp core anti- matter containment check
注意 曲速核反物质密封检查
in three minutes.
将在3分钟后开始
Captain！I'm so sorry about Admiral Pike.
舰长 派克上将的事我很遗憾
We all are.
我们都很遗憾
- Are you okay？- Fine，thank you，Lieutenant.
- 你还好吗 - 没事 谢谢你上尉
Actually，Scotty just quit.
其实 小科刚辞职了
And your boyfriend's second- guessing me every chance he gets.
你男友不放过任何机会指责我
I'm sorry，that was inappropriate.
抱歉 我失言了
It's just sometimes I want to rip the bangs off his head.
有时我真想把他的刘海扯下来
- You know，maybe it's me。I… - It's not you.
- 可能是我…- 不关你事
It's not？
不是吗
Wait，are you guys… are you guys fighting？
等等 你们两个吵架了吗
I'd rather not talk about it，sir.
我不想谈这个 长官
Oh，my God！What is that even like？
天啊 你们两个居然会吵架
Your ears burning？
你耳朵烫吗
Captain on the bridge！
舰长到达舰桥
Captain.
舰长
Mr。Chekov。You've been shadowing Mr。Scott.
切科夫先生 你一直在斯科特先生手下做事
You are familiar with the engineering systems of this ship？
你熟悉这艘星舰的工程系统吗
Affirmative，sir.
熟悉 长官
Good.
很好
You're my new Chief。Go put on a red shirt.
你就是我的新轮机长 穿上红色制服
Aye，Captain.
遵命 舰长
Retract all moorings，Mr。Sulu.
收回所有系泊设备 苏鲁先生
Yes，sir.
遵命 长官
Docking clamps one，two，and three are released.
对接夹一二三号已释放
All moorings retracted.
所有系泊设备已收回
Lieutenant Uhura，open a shipwide channel.
乌胡拉上尉 打开全舰频道
Yes，sir.
遵命 长官
Mr。Chekov，how we looking down there？
切科夫 星舰状态如何
- All systems nominal，Captain。- Copy that.
- 所有系统正常 舰长 - 收到
Warp available at your command.
随时可以开始曲速飞行
Thank you，Mr。Chekov.
谢谢 切科夫先生
- All right。Let's ride。- Yes，sir.
- 很好 出发 - 遵命 长官
Channel open，sir.
频道已开启 长官
Attention，crew of the Enterprise.
注意 进取号的全体成员
As most of you know，Christopher Pike，
你们大多已经知道 克里斯托弗·派克
former captain of this ship and our friend，
这艘星舰的前舰长 我们的朋友
is dead.
去世了
The man who killed him has fled our system
杀死他的人逃离了我们的管辖区域
and is hiding on the Klingon homeworld，
现藏身于克林贡人的母星
somewhere he believes we are unwilling to go.
他以为我们不会去那里
We are on our way there now.
而我们现在正在路上
Per Admiral Marcus，
马科斯上将有命
it is essential that our presence go undetected.
不得被敌人发现我们的踪迹
Tensions between the Federation
联邦和克林贡帝国的关系
and the Klingon Empire have been high.
高度紧张
Any provocation could lead to an all- out war.
任何挑衅行为都可能导致全面战争
I will personally lead a landing party
我将亲自率领部队
to an abandoned city on the surface of Kronos
登陆克隆那斯的一座废弃城市
where we will capture the fugitive，John Harrison，
我们将在那里俘获逃犯约翰·哈里森
and return him to Earth so he can face judgment for his actions.
并将他带回地球 接受审判
All right。Let's go get this son of a bitch。Kirk out.
我们去抓这个畜生吧 柯克发言结束
Captain，I believe you have made the right decision.
舰长 我觉得你的决定是正确的
If I can be of assistance，
如果我能帮得上忙
I would be happy to accompany you on the away team.
我很乐意陪你去
You？Happy？
你 乐意
I was simply attempting to use your vernacular to convey an idea.
我只是试图用你们的语言来表达
Thank you，Mr。Spock.
谢谢 斯波克先生
All personnel，prepare for the closing of payload bay doors.
全体人员请注意 储藏舱门即将关闭
Mr。Spock。You startled me.
斯波克先生 你吓到我了
What are you doing，Doctor？
你在做什么 博士
- Verifying that the torpedo's internal… - You misunderstand.
- 检验鱼雷内部 - 你误会了
What are you doing aboard this ship？
我问的是 你来这艘星舰做什么
There is no record of you being assigned to the Enterprise.
没有记录显示你被派遣到进取号
Really？That must be some sort of mistake.
是吗 肯定哪里搞错了
My conclusion as well，Dr。Marcus.
我也是这样想的 马科斯博士
Except that you have lied about your identity.
除非你撒谎隐瞒了身份
Wallace is the surname of your mother.
华莱士是你母亲的姓氏
I can only assume the Admiral is your father.
我只能假设上将是你的父亲
Mr。Spock.
斯波克先生
I'm aware that I have no right to ask this of you.
我知道我没资格向你提要求
But please，he cannot know that I'm here.
但是求你了 不能让他知道我在这
Engineering manually dropped us out of warp，sir.
曲速飞行被工程部人工关闭 长官
Mr。Chekov，did you break my ship？
切科夫先生 是你把星舰弄坏了吗
Sorry，sir。I don't know what happened！
对不起 长官 我不知道怎么回事
The core overheated.
内核过热
I had to activate the emergency stop.
我不得不紧急停止
It must be a coolant leak.
一定是冷却剂泄漏了
I need time to find it.
一时半会找不到泄漏点
- Sorry，Captain。- Damn it.
- 对不起 舰长 - 该死
Mr。Sulu，time to our destination.
苏鲁先生 还有多久到达目的地
Twenty minutes，sir.
20分钟 长官
That's 20 minutes in enemy space we were't counting on.
我们将在敌人领空飞行 而且毫无准备
All right。We better hop to it.
那我们得抓紧时间了
- Where's Spock？- Here，Captain.
- 斯波克呢 - 在这 舰长
You're coming with me to Kronos.
你跟我一起去克隆那斯
Lieutenant，how's your Klingon？
上尉 你克林贡语水平如何
It's rusty，but it's good.
有些生疏 但是没问题
Good，you're coming，too.
很好 你也一起来
This isn't going to be a problem，is it，
你们两个一起工作
you two working together？
没什么问题吧
Absolutely not.
绝对没问题
Unclear.
不确定
I'll meet you in the shuttle bay.
穿梭机舱见
Jim，you're not actually going down there，are you？
吉姆 你不会是真要下去吧
You don't rob a bank when the getaway car has a flat tire.
车都爆胎了还怎么抢银行啊
I'm sure engineering will have us all patched up
我相信等我们回来的时候
by the time we get back.
工程部会把动力装置修好的
Isn't that right，Mr。Chekov？
对吧 切科夫先生
Yes，Captain.
是的 舰长
I'll do my best，sir.
我尽力 长官
Mr。Sulu，you have the conn.
苏鲁先生 你来操舵
Once we're en route，I want you to transmit
我们一出发 你就对准
a targeted comm burst to Harrison's location.
哈里森的位置发射通讯信号
You tell him you have a bunch of real big torpedoes
告诉他有一堆杀伤力极强的鱼雷
pointed at his head
正瞄着他的脑袋
and if he doesn't play nice，you're not afraid to use them.
如果他不就范 你就会发射鱼雷
- Is that a problem？- No，sir.
- 有问题吗 - 没有 长官
I've just never sat in the chair before.
只是我从没坐过舰长椅
You're gonna do great.
你会做得很好的
Jim！Wait！
吉姆 等等
You just sat that man down at a high- stakes poker game
你刚刚让他参加了一场高风险的赌博
with no cards and told him to bluff.
手里没好牌 还要他虚张声势
Now Sulu's a good man，but he is no captain.
苏鲁确实很出色 但他不是当舰长的料
For the next two hours，he is.
接下来的两个小时 他就是舰长
And enough with the metaphors，all right？That's an order.
别再打比方了好吗 这是命令
Mr。Sulu，
苏鲁先生
make sure that K'normian ship is ready to fly.
让那艘克诺米安的飞船做好飞行准备
Acting Captain Sulu to Shuttle Bay 2.
代理舰长苏鲁呼叫2号穿梭机舱
Please have the trade ship we confiscated
请把我们上个月没收的商用飞船
during the Mudd incident last month fueled and flight ready.
加满燃料 并做好飞行准备
Captain Kirk is en route to you now.
柯克舰长正在前往
Ready to deploy，Captain.
一切就绪 舰长
Lieutenants，lose the red shirts.
上尉们 请脱掉红衬衫
You are K'normian arms dealers。Put those on.
你们现在是克诺米安军火商 穿上这个
- Sir？- Look，if this thing goes south，
- 长官 - 如果情况不妙
there can be nothing tying us to Starfleet.
绝对不能和星际舰队扯上干系
Unless of course you want to start a war，Mr。Hendorff.
除非你想引发战争 亨多夫先生
- No，sir。- No，sir.
- 不想 长官 - 不想 长官
Good。Me，neither.
很好 我也不想
I am detecting a single life sign in the Ketha Province.
检测到凯萨区有一个生命迹象
Given the information provided by Mr。Scott，
根据斯科特提供的信息来看
this is most likely John Harrison.
那很可能就是约翰·哈里森
Mr。Sulu，I think we found our man.
苏鲁 我想我们找到他了
You let him know you mean business.
告诉他我们不是开玩笑的
Aye，Captain.
是 舰长
Attention，John Harrison.
听着 约翰·哈里森
This is Captain Hikaru Sulu of the U.S.S。Enterprise.
我是联邦星舰进取号舰长苏鲁田光
A shuttle of highly trained officers
几位训练有素的军官正在驾驶穿梭机
is on its way to your location.
飞向你的位置
If you do not surrender to them immediately，
如果你不立即向他们投降
I will unleash the entire payload of
我会将本舰上
advanced long- range torpedoes
所有高级远程鱼雷
currently locked onto your location.
向你发射
You have two minutes to confirm your compliance.
你有两分钟时间投降
Refusal to do so will result in your obliteration.
否则你将粉身碎骨
If you test me，you will fail.
别试探我 那是自取灭亡
Mr。Sulu，
苏鲁先生
remind me never to piss you off.
我再也不敢惹你了
（克隆那斯）
We will arrive at Harrison's location
我们将在三分钟后
in three minutes，Captain.
到达哈里森的位置 舰长
It is unlikely that he will come willingly.
他不太可能会主动投降
I calculate the odds of him attempting to kill us
我计算出他会试图杀掉我们的概率是
at 91.6%.
91.6%
Fantastic.
非常好
Good thing you don't care about dying.
还好你不怕死
I am sorry，Lieutenant。I could not hear what you said.
抱歉 上尉 我没听清你说什么
I didn't say anything.
我没说什么
Actually，I'd be happy to speak
其实 你要是肯听
- if you're willing to listen to me。- Guys…
- 我倒是很乐意说 - 伙计们
Lieutenant，I would prefer to discuss this in private.
上尉 我们最好私下谈
You'd prefer not to discuss this at all.
你根本就不想谈
Our current circumstances…
我们目前的状况
Are you really gonna do this right now？
你非要现在说这些吗
What never seems to require your undivided focus…
你唯一没有专注的事情
I'm sorry，Captain，just two seconds.
抱歉 舰长 就一会儿
- Okay。- is us.
- 好吧 - 就是我们的感情
At that volcano，you didn't give a thought to us.
在火山那里 你完全没考虑我们的感情
What it would do to me if you died，Spock.
你死了我怎么办 斯波克
You didn't feel anything.
你太无情了
You didn't care.
你也不在乎
And I'm not the only one who's upset with you.
不止我感到生气
The Captain is，too.
舰长也是
No，no，no。Don't drag me into this.
没 没 别把我扯进来
She is right.
她说得对
Your suggestion that I do not care about dying is incorrect.
你说我不在乎生死 这不正确
A sentient being's optimal chance
有意识的生物若要最大程度发挥自身作用
at maximizing their utility is a long and prosperous life.
最佳选择是长久而富足的生命
Great.
好极了
Not exactly a love song，Spock.
这不太像情话 斯波克
You misunderstand.
你误解了
It is true I chose not to feel anything
在意识到自己命不久矣时
upon realizing that my own life was ending.
我确实选择了摒弃感情
As Admiral Pike was dying，
派克上将临终前
I joined with his consciousness
我连通了他的意识
and experienced what he felt at the moment of his passing.
体会到了他临终时的情感
Anger。Confusion.
愤怒 困惑
Loneliness.
孤独
Fear.
恐惧
I had experienced those feelings before，
我也曾体会过这些
multiplied exponentially
而我的星球被摧毁的那天
on the day my planet was destroyed.
这些情感变得极度强烈
Such a feeling is something
这样的情感
I choose never to experience again.
我永远不想再体会
Nyota，you mistake my choice not to feel
尼欧塔 你误以为我选择摒弃感情
as a reflection of my not caring.
是因为我不在乎
Well，I assure you，the truth is precisely the opposite.
我向你保证 事实恰恰相反
What the hell was that？
怎么回事
What happened？Where's their signal？
发生了什么事 他们的信号呢
It cut out。I'm working to get them back.
中断了 我正在重新连接
We are being pursued by a D- 4 class Klingon vessel.
我们正被一艘D- 4级克林贡飞船追击
I thought this sector was abandoned！
这里不是废墟吗
It must be a random patrol.
一定是碰巧遇到巡逻
Hold on！
坐稳了
This ship has no offensive capabilities.
我们这艘船没有任何攻击能力
It's got us。Give me all six fuel cells.
有我们呢 启动全部6块燃料电池
Aye，Captain.
是 舰长
Damn it！
该死
They're closing fast，bearing 285！
他们正在迅速逼进 方位285
All right，there！There！We can lose them there.
那里 我们可以在那里甩掉他们
If you are suggesting that we utilize the passage
如果你想通过前方建筑物间的
between the approaching structures，
那条缝隙
- this ship will not fit。- We'll fit.
- 我们过不去的 - 能过去
Captain，we will not fit.
舰长 我们过不去
We'll fit，we'll fit！
能过去 能过去
- I told you we'd fit。- I am not sure that qualifies.
- 说了我们能过去 - 这种过法不算
Any sign of them？
还看得见他们吗
No。Which worries me.
没有 这正是我担心的
We lost them！
我们甩掉他们了
Or they're jamming our scanners.
也许是扫描器被干扰了
Or we lost them.
更也许是甩掉他们了
They're ordering us to land.
他们命令我们着陆
Captain，they're gonna want to know why we're here.
舰长 他们会想知道我们来这里的目的
And they're gonna torture us.
他们会折磨我们
Question us.
审问我们
And they're gonna kill us.
最后杀掉我们
So we come out shooting.
那我们出去跟他们拼了
We're outnumbered，outgunned.
我们寡不敌众 火力又不够
There's no way we survive if we attack first.
如果先动手 肯定会死
You brought me here because I speak Klingon.
你带我来是因为我会克林贡语
Then let me speak Klingon.
就让我去和他们谈吧
This isn't going to work.
这样没用的
It is our only logical option.
这是唯一合乎逻辑的选择
And if you interrupt her now，
如果你现在阻止她
you will not only incur the wrath of the Klingons
不仅会激怒克林贡人
but that of Lieutenant Uhura as well.
也会激怒乌胡拉上尉
我是来帮助你们的
- Lieutenant。- Thanks，Captain.
- 上尉 - 谢谢 舰长
我无意冒犯
有个罪犯藏在这片废墟中
他杀了很多人类
我为什么要在乎一个人类杀人犯
因为你在乎荣誉
而这个人毫无荣誉可言
你和你的人也有危险
- Stand down。- How many torpedoes？
- 放下武器 - 有几枚鱼雷
Stand down！
放下武器
The torpedoes，the weapons
你在通讯中
you threatened me with in your message.
用来威胁我的那些鱼雷
How many are there？
一共有多少
Seventy- two.
72枚
I surrender.
我投降
On behalf of Christopher Pike，
我代表克里斯托弗·派克
my friend，
我的朋友
I accept your surrender.
接受你的投降
Captain！
舰长
Captain.
Cuff him.
给他戴上手铐
Bones，meet me in the brig.
老骨头 在禁闭室那里等我
Be right there.
马上就到
Lieutenant.
上尉
Contact Starfleet，
联系星际舰队
let them know we have Harrison in custody，
告诉他们我们抓到了哈里森
and we'll be on our way once the warp core is repaired.
等曲速核修好了我们就马上回去
Yes，sir.
是的 长官
- Why the hell did he surrender？- I don't know.
- 他到底为什么会投降 - 不知道
But he just took out a squad of Klingons single- handedly.
他凭一己之力解决了一队克林贡人
I want to know how.
我要知道他是怎么做到的
Sounds like we have a superman on board.
看来我们抓了一个超人
You tell me.
一点没错
Put your arm through the hole。I'm gonna take a blood sample.
胳膊伸出来 我要提取血样
Why aren't we moving，Captain？
我们怎么还没走 舰长
An unexpected malfunction，perhaps in your warp core
曲速核发生了什么意外故障
conveniently stranding you on the edge of Klingon space？
恰好使你们在克林贡领空边缘搁浅了吗
- How the hell do you know that？- Bones.
- 你怎么知道 - 老骨头
I think you'd find my insight valuable，Captain.
你会发现我洞察力很可贵 舰长
- We good？- Yeah.
- 抽好了吗 - 是的
Let me know what you find.
有什么发现要告诉我
Ignore me and you will get everyone on this ship killed.
忽视我就是将船上的所有人置身死地
Captain，I believe he will only attempt to manipulate you.
舰长 我觉得他只是想摆布你
I would not recommend engaging the prisoner further.
我建议不要与他继续交谈
Give me a minute.
给我一点时间
Let me explain what's happening here.
我来告诉你现在的情况
You are a criminal.
你是个罪犯
I watched you murder innocent men and women.
我亲眼目睹你杀了无辜的人们
I was authorized to end you！
上头给我的命令是消灭你
And the only reason why you are still alive
你仍然活着的唯一原因
is because I am allowing it.
就是我允许你活着
So shut your mouth.
所以给我闭嘴
Oh，Captain，are you going to punch me again
舰长 你是想再打我一顿
over and over till your arm weakens？
一直打到胳膊酸为止吗
Clearly you want to，so tell me，
很明显你想 那么你说
why did you allow me to live？
为什么你还允许我活着
We all make mistakes.
我们都会犯错
No。I surrendered to you because，
不 我之所以投降
despite your attempt to convince me otherwise，
是因为 虽然你想告诉我你心狠手辣
you seem to have a conscience，Mr。Kirk.
但你貌似有良心 柯克先生
If you did not，then it would be impossible for me
如果你没有 你也就不会
to convince you of the truth.
相信我所说的真相
23-17-46-11.
23-17-46-11
Coordinates not far from Earth.
这是地球附近的坐标点
If you want to know why I did what I did，
如果你想知道我为什么做了这些
go and take a look.
就去那里看看
Give me one reason why I should listen to you.
给我一个让我相信你的理由
I can give you 72.
我可以给你72个理由
And they're on board your ship，Captain.
它们都在船上 舰长
They have been all along.
一直都在船上
I suggest you open one up.
我建议你打开一个看看
（旧金山港）
You know what really bothers me，though？
你知道我真正纠结的是什么吗
It's the modifications，you know，the enhancements.
就是那些修正 改进什么的
Right？And then like that，I'm off the ship！
然后我就这样被赶下星舰了
Just for trying to do what's right！
就因为坚持要做正确的事情
And what did you do anyway？
你当时为什么一声不吭
You just stood there like an oyster，
你只是像个傻逼似的站在那里
looking at me！
看着我
What？
什么事
Scotty，it's Kirk.
小科 我是柯克
Well now！
来得正是时候
If it isn't Captain James Tiberius Perfect Hair！
这不是詹姆斯大帝舰长衰锅吗
Did you hear that？I called him Perfect Hair.
听到了吗 我叫他衰锅
- Where are you？- Where are you？
- 你在哪 - 你在哪
Are you drunk？
你喝醉了吗
What I do in my private time is my business，Jimbo.
我的时间我做主 小吉吉
I need you to help me out with something.
我有事要你帮忙
Will you take these coordinates down？
你能记下这个坐标吗
23-17-46-11.
23-17-46-11
Are you writing？
写下来了吗
What，you don't think I can remember four numbers？
你觉得我连四个数都记不住吗
Ye of little faith。What was the third one？
太小瞧我了 第三个数是什么
Forty- six.
I don't know exactly what you're looking for，
我不知道你该去找什么
but I have a feeling you'll know it when you see it.
但是我有预感 你看到就知道了
You may have been right about those torpedoes.
关于这些鱼雷 也许你是对的
I will consider that an apology.
我就把这当成道歉吧
And I will consider that apology.
我会考虑接受你的道歉的
You are the one who quit.
是你主动辞职的
You made me quit！
你逼我辞职的
Mr。Scott？
斯科特先生
Scott.
斯科特
The nerve of that guy！
这家伙脸皮真厚
I am not doing that man any favors！
我才不帮他呢
No！
不帮
All right，then！
好吧
Are you out of your corn- fed mind？
你脑子进水了吗
You're not actually going to listen to this guy？
你不会真的要相信那家伙吧
He killed Pike，he almost killed you，
他杀了派克 还差点杀了你
and now you think it's a good idea to pop open a torpedo
现在你竟然想撬开鱼雷
because he dared you to.
就因为他让你撬
Why did he save our lives，Bones？
他为什么要救我们 老骨头
The Doctor does have a point，Captain.
医生说的有道理 舰长
Don't agree with me，Spock。It makes me very uncomfortable.
别赞同我 斯波克 这让我很不自在
Perhaps you，too，should learn to govern your emotions，Doctor.
也许你也该学着控制情绪了 医生
In this situation，logic dictates…
现在的情形下 根据逻辑
Logic？Oh，my God！There's a maniac
逻辑 天啊
trying to make us blow up our own damn ship and…
有个疯子想让我们炸毁自己的星舰
That's not it。I don't know why he surrendered，
不是这样的 我不知道他为什么会投降
but that's not it.
但肯定不是为了炸掉星舰
Look，we're gonna open a torpedo。The question is how.
我们必须打开鱼雷 问题是怎么打开
But，Jim，without Mr。Scott on board，
但是 吉姆 斯科特先生不在船上
who exactly is qualified
谁还有能力
to just pop open a four- ton stick of dynamite？
去撬开一个四吨重的炸弹
The Admiral's daughter appeared to have interest in the torpedoes
上将的女儿似乎对那些鱼雷感兴趣
and she is a weapons specialist.
而且她是武器专家
Perhaps she could be of some use.
也许她可以
What Admiral's daughter？
什么上将的女儿
Carol Marcus。Your new science officer
卡罗尔·马科斯 你的新科学专员
concealed her identity to board the ship.
她为了上船而隐瞒了身份
When were you going to tell me that？
你打算什么时候告诉我
When it became relevant。As it just did.
必要的时候 就像现在
Are the torpedoes in the weapons bay？
鱼雷在武器舱吗
Loaded and ready to fire。What are they？
已装载 随时可发射 它们是什么
I don't know。That's why I forged my transfer
不知道 所以我伪造了调任令
onto your ship to find out why.
上船来一探究竟
I do apologize for that.
对此我很抱歉
By the way，if I caused you any problems，I am sorry.
如果对你造成了什么麻烦 对不起
I'm Carol Marcus.
我叫卡罗尔·马科斯
- James Kirk。- Torpedoes.
- 詹姆斯·柯克 - 鱼雷
My father gave me access to every program he oversaw，
我父亲准许我查看他监管的所有项目
then I heard he was developing these prototype torpedoes.
然后我听说他在开发这些鱼雷样品
When I went to confront him about it，
我去和他探讨此事
he wouldn't even see me.
他甚至都不见我
That's when I discovered the torpedoes had disappeared
就在那个时候 我发现这些鱼雷
from all official records.
从官方记录中消失了
And then he gave them to me.
然后他把它们给了我
You're much cleverer than your reputation suggests，Captain Kirk.
你比传说中聪明得多 柯克舰长
I have a reputation？
我还小有名气吗
Yes，you do。I'm a friend of Christine Chapel's.
是的 克莉丝汀·查普尔是我朋友
Christine，yes。How is she？
克莉丝汀啊 她好吗
She transferred to the outer frontier to be a nurse.
她被调到外边界当护士去了
She's much happier now.
现在比以前开心多了
That's good.
那很好啊
You have no idea who I'm talking about，do you？
你根本不知道我在说谁吧
What are we doing in here？
我们来这里干什么
Is this shuttle prepped to fly？
这架穿梭机随时可以起飞吗
Of course it is.
当然可以
- Would you please turn around？- Why？
- 你能转过身去吗 - 为什么
Just turn around.
转过去就是了
It's too dangerous to try and open
在进取号上尝试打开鱼雷
one of these torpedoes on the Enterprise.
实在是太危险了
But there is a nearby planetoid.
但这附近有个小行星
I can open one up there.
我可以在那里打开
But I will need some help.
但我需要帮助
Turn around.
转过去啊
Now！
快点
Captain on the bridge！
舰长到达舰桥
Mr。Sulu，
苏鲁先生
have Doctors Marcus and McCoy landed on the planetoid yet？
马科斯博士和麦科伊医生到小行星了吗
Yes，sir.
是的 长官
They're moving the torpedo into position now.
他们正在把鱼雷移到指定位置
Good。Any activity from the Klingons？
很好 有克林贡人的活动迹象吗
Not yet.
目前没有
But if we're stuck here much longer，
但是如果我们在这儿耽搁太久
they will find us.
就一定会被他们发现
Lieutenant Uhura，did you let Starfleet know
乌胡拉上尉 你是否已经通知星际舰队
we have Harrison in custody？
我们抓到了哈里森
Yes，sir。No response yet.
是的 长官 目前没有回应
Engineering to bridge.
工程部呼叫舰桥
Hello。Captain，can you hear me？
喂 舰长 能听到我说话吗
Mr。Chekov，give me some good news.
切科夫先生 说点好消息
We found the leak，sir，but the damage is substantial.
找到泄漏点了 长官 但损伤很大
We're working on it.
我们正在抢修
Any idea what caused it？
知道是什么原因造成的吗
No，sir。But I accept full responsibility.
不知道 长官 不过我会负全责
Something tells me it wasn't your fault。Stay on it.
直觉告诉我这不是你的错 继续工作吧
Shuttle is standing by，Captain.
与穿梭机的通讯已连接 舰长
Bones，thanks for helping out.
老骨头 谢谢你的帮忙
Dr。Marcus asked for the steadiest hands on the ship.
马科斯博士想要船上手最稳的人
You know，when I dreamt about being stuck
我幻想和一个美女一起
on a deserted planet with a gorgeous woman，
被困在一个荒芜的星球上的时候
there was no torpedo！
我没幻想那里有鱼雷
Dr。McCoy，may I remind you，
麦科伊医生 给你提个醒
you are not there to flirt.
你不是去那里泡妞的
So how can these legendary hands help you，Dr。Marcus？
这双传说之手该怎么帮你 马科斯博士
Bones！
老骨头
To understand how powerful these weapons are，
要了解这些武器的威力
we need to open the warhead.
就要打开弹头
To do that，we need to access the fuel compartment.
要打开弹头 我们就要进入燃料舱
Unfortunately for us，
但不幸的是
the warheads on these weapons are live.
这些武器的弹头已经被激活了
Sweetheart，I once performed
甜心 我曾经给怀孕的葛恩人
an emergency C- section on a pregnant Gorn.
做过一次紧急剖腹产手术
Octuplets.
八胞胎
And let me tell you，those little bastards bite.
告诉你 那些小畜生会咬人
I think I can work some magic on your missile.
我觉得我可以给你的导弹施加点魔力
Dr。McCoy，there's a bundle of fiber optic cables
麦科伊医生 有一束光纤电缆
against the inner casing.
抵住了内套管
You'll need to cut the 23rd wire down.
你需要切断第23根线
Whatever you do，do not touch anything else.
无论如何 都不要碰到其它东西
Do you understand？
明白吗
Right。The thought never crossed my mind.
明白 我想也没想过
Dr。McCoy，
麦科伊医生
wait for my word.
等我指令
I'm rerouting the detonation processor.
我正在将引爆处理器改道
- Are you ready？- And raring.
- 准备好了吗 - 等不及了
Good luck.
祝你好运
Sir，the torpedo just armed itself.
长官 鱼雷自我启动了
The warhead's gonna detonate in 30 seconds，sir！
弹头将在30秒后引爆 长官
What the hell happened？I can't get my arm out！
发生了什么事 我胳膊卡住了
Target their signal。Beam them back right now.
锁定他们的信号 马上把他们传送回来
The transporter cannot differentiate
传送装置区别不了
between Dr。McCoy and the torpedo.
麦科伊医生和鱼雷
We cannot beam back one without the other.
只能两个一起传送回来
Dr。Marcus，can you disarm it？
马科斯博士 你能否将它关闭
I'm trying。I'm trying.
我在想办法 我在想办法
Jim，get her the hell out of here！
吉姆 快让她离开这里
No！If you beam me back，he dies！
不行 如果把我送回去 他就死定了
Just let me do it！
让我拆吧
Ten。Nine.
十 九
Eight.
八
Standing by to transport Dr。Marcus
准备传送马科斯博士
on your command，sir.
请随时下令 长官
Four。Three.
四 三
Shit！
该死的
Deactivation successful，Captain.
成功解除激活 舰长
Dr。McCoy，are you all right？
麦科伊医生 你没事吧
Bones！
老骨头
Jim？
吉姆
You're going to want to see this.
你一定对这个感兴趣
（坐标23.17.46.11 木星）
Delta team，
D队
deliver your thrusters to loading dock 12.
把你们的推进器运到12号装货码头
U.S.S。Vengeance，bridge crew
这里是联邦星舰复仇号的舰桥人员
requesting entry to construction hangar.
请求进入建设机库
You are cleared to enter the hangar.
准许进入机库
I need a welding team on the number one nacelle.
一号机舱需要一个焊接小组
Holy…
我的天…
What have we got？
有什么发现
It's quite clever actually.
设计者很聪明
This fuel container's been removed from the torpedo
把燃料箱从鱼雷中移除
and retrofitted to hide this cryo tube.
并改装用于隐藏这个冷冻管
- Is he alive？- He's alive.
- 他还活着吗 - 还活着
But if we try to revive him
但如果我们尝试去唤醒他
without the proper sequencing，it could kill him.
却没有按照正确的步骤 反而会害死他
This technology's beyond me.
我不懂这项技术
How advanced，Doctor？
有多先进 医生
It's not advanced。That cryo tube is ancient.
不是先进 那个冷冻管很古老了
We haven't needed to freeze anyone
自从我们发明了曲速飞行
since we developed warp capability，
就不需要把人冷冻了
which explains the most interesting thing about our friend here.
正好解释了这位朋友最有意思的一点
He's 300 years old.
他有300岁了
Why is there a man in that torpedo？
为什么鱼雷里会有个人
There are men and women in all those torpedoes，Captain.
所有的鱼雷里都有人 舰长
I put them there.
是我把他们放进去的
Who the hell are you？
你到底是谁
A remnant of a time long past.
历史的遗迹
Genetically engineered to be superior
通过基因改造变得强大
so as to lead others to peace in a world at war.
好引导其他人从战争走向和平
But we were condemned as criminals，forced into exile.
但是我们被裁定为罪犯 被流放
For centuries we slept，
我们沉睡了数个世纪
hoping when we awoke，things would be different.
期待醒来后 一切都会改变
But as a result of the destruction of Vulcan，
但是瓦肯星毁灭带来的结果是
your Starfleet began to aggressively search
你们星际舰队开始积极地探索
distant quadrants of space.
浩瀚遥远的宇宙空间
My ship was found adrift.
我的船被发现时正在太空中飘荡
I alone was revived.
仅我一人被唤醒了
I looked up 「John Harrison.」
我查过约翰·哈里森
Until a year ago，he didn't exist.
一年之前 他还不存在
John Harrison was a fiction created the moment I was awoken
你们的马科斯上将为了他的事业将我唤醒
by your Admiral Marcus to help him advance his cause.
约翰·哈里森这个假身份始于那个时候
A smokescreen to conceal my true identity.
这是用来隐藏我真实身份的障眼法
My name is
我真名叫
Khan.
可汗
Why would a Starfleet Admiral
为什么一个星际舰队的上将
ask a 300- year- old frozen man for help？
会求助于一个被冰冻的300岁的人
Because I am better.
因为我更出色
- At what？- Everything.
- 哪方面 - 所有方面
Alexander Marcus needed to respond to
亚历山大·马科斯需要在文明时代
an uncivilized threat in a civilized time
对一个野蛮的威胁作出回应
and for that he needed a warrior's mind.
为此他需要一颗战士的头脑
My mind.
我的头脑
To design weapons and warships.
来设计武器和战舰
You are suggesting the Admiral
你的意思是
violated every regulation he vowed to uphold
上将违反了所有他发誓要遵守的规定
simply because he wanted to exploit your intellect.
就因为他想借用你的智慧
He wanted to exploit my savagery.
他想借用我的野性
Intellect alone is useless in a fight，Mr。Spock.
战斗光靠智慧是不够的 斯波克先生
You… You can't even break a rule.
你…你连规矩都不敢打破
How would you be expected to break bone？
又怎么杀得了人
Marcus used me to design weapons.
马科斯利用我制造武器
To help him realize his vision of a militarized Starfleet.
帮助他实现建造军事化舰队的愿望
He sent you to use those weapons.
他让你使用那些武器
To fire my torpedoes on an unsuspecting planet.
把我的鱼雷发射到一个毫无戒心的星球
And then he purposely crippled your ship
然后他故意在敌方地盘弄坏你的船
in enemy space，leading to one inevitable outcome.
从而导致一个不可避免的结果
The Klingons would come searching
克林贡人会去寻找
for whomever was responsible，
是谁发射了鱼雷
and you would have no chance of escape.
然后你只能束手待毙
Marcus would finally have the war he talked about.
最终马科斯所说的战争就会发生
The war he always wanted.
那是他一直想要的战争
No。No.
不 不
I watched you open fire
我亲眼见你朝着一屋子
in a room full of unarmed Starfleet officers.
手无寸铁的星际舰队军官开火
You killed them in cold blood！
你冷血地杀害了他们
Marcus took my crew from me.
马科斯夺走了我的船员
You are a murderer！
你是个杀人凶手
He used my friends to control me.
他利用我的朋友来控制我
I tried to smuggle them to safety
我想偷偷地把他们运到安全的地方
by concealing them in the very weapons I had designed，
我把他们藏在了我设计的武器当中
but I was discovered.
但是被发现了
I had no choice but to escape alone.
我没有办法 只能自己逃走
And when I did，I had every reason to suspect
逃走后 我只能相信
that Marcus had killed every single one
马科斯杀了每一个
of the people I hold most dear.
我最最在乎的人
So I responded in kind.
所以我以牙还牙
My crew
我的船员
is my family，Kirk.
就是我的家人 柯克
Is there anything you would not do for your family？
你愿意为你的家人赴汤蹈火吗
Proximity alert，sir！
有物体接近 长官
There's a ship at warp heading right for us.
一艘曲速飞行中的星舰正迎面向我们驶来
- Klingons？- At warp？
- 是克林贡人吗 - 曲速飞行中？
No，Kirk.
不 柯克
- We both know who it is。- I don't think so.
- 我们都知道是谁 - 不是他们
It's not coming at us from Kronos.
不是从克隆那斯飞过来的
Lieutenant，move Khan to med bay.
上尉 带可汗去医务舱
Post six security officers on him.
派六名警卫看着他
Yes，Captain.
遵命 舰长
Captain on the bridge！
舰长到达舰桥
ETA of the incoming ship.
该星舰的预计到达时间
Three seconds，sir.
三秒 长官
- Shields。- Aye，Captain.
- 开启防护盾 - 是 舰长
They're hailing us，sir.
他们在呼叫我们 长官
On screen.
接到大屏幕
Broadcast shipwide，for the record.
全舰播放 以供记录在案
Captain Kirk.
柯克舰长
Admiral Marcus。I wasn't expecting you.
马科斯上将 没想到是您
That's a hell of a ship you got there.
您的船真是帅呆了
And I wasn't expecting to get word
我也没想到会接到消息说
that you'd taken Harrison into custody
你违抗命令
in violation of your orders.
将哈里森拘捕了
Well，we…
我们…
We had to improvise when our warp core
我们的曲速核发生了意外故障
unexpectedly malfunctioned.
我们得随机应变
But you already knew that，didn't you，sir？
但您已经知道了 不是吗 长官
I don't take your meaning.
我不懂你的意思
Well，that's why you're here，isn't it？
您来这里不就是因为这个吗
To assist with our repairs？
帮我们修理星舰
Why else would the head of Starfleet
否则还有什么理由会让
personally come to the edge of the Neutral Zone？
星际战队的首领亲自来到中立区的边缘
Captain，they're scanning our ship.
舰长 他们在扫描我们的船
Is there something I can help you find，sir？
需要我帮您找什么吗 长官
Where is your prisoner，Kirk？
你的囚犯在哪 柯克
Per Starfleet regulation，
按照星际舰队的规定
I'm planning on returning Khan to Earth to stand trial.
我打算将可汗带回地球受审
Well，shit.
该死
You talked to him.
你和他说过话
This is exactly what I was hoping to spare you from.
这正是我不希望你蹚的浑水
I took a tactical risk and I woke that bastard up，
我冒着风险唤醒了那个混蛋
believing that his superior intelligence
相信他卓越的才智
could help us protect ourselves
可以保护我们
from whatever came at us next.
无论敌人是谁
But I made a mistake.
但是我错了
And now the blood of everybody he's killed is on my hands.
现在他杀了这么多人 我难辞其咎
So I'm asking you，
所以我请求你
give him to me
把他交给我
so that I can end what I started.
好让我收拾好自己的烂摊子
And what exactly would you like me to do
你想让我怎么处理
with the rest of his crew，sir？
他剩下的船员 长官
Fire them at the Klingons？End 72 lives？
把他们发射给克林贡人 结束72条性命
Start a war in the process？
顺便挑起一场战争吗
He put those people in those torpedoes.
是他把那些人放进鱼雷里的
And I simply didn't want to burden you
我只是不想增加你的负担
with knowing what was inside of them.
才没让你知道里面是什么
You saw what this man can do all by himself.
你也见到了这家伙单打独斗的能力
Can you imagine what would happen
要是把其他船员唤醒
if we woke up the rest of his crew？
你能想象会发生什么吗
What else did he tell you？That he's a peacekeeper？
他还跟你说了什么 说他是维和部队吗
He's playing you，son，don't you see that？
他在耍你 孩子 你看不出来吗
Khan and his crew were condemned to death as war criminals.
可汗和他的船员是战犯 已被判处死刑
And now it is our duty to carry out that sentence
现在我们有责任在他杀害更多人之前
before anybody else dies because of him.
把他们处死
Now，I'm going to ask you again！
现在 我再问你一遍
One last time，son.
最后一遍 孩子
Lower your shields.
放下你们的防护盾
Tell me where he is.
告诉我他在哪里
He's in engineering，sir.
他在工程部 长官
But I'll have him moved
但我会马上把他
to the transporter room right away.
带到传送室去
I'll take it from here.
剩下的就交给我了
Do not drop those shields，
不要放下防护盾
- Mr。Sulu。- Aye，Captain.
- 苏鲁先生 - 是 舰长
Captain，given your awareness
舰长 鉴于你知道
of Khan's true location in the med bay，
可汗的真实位置在医务舱
may I know the details of your plan？
我能知道你计划的细节吗
I told Marcus we were bringing a fugitive back to Earth.
我告诉马科斯我们要把逃犯带回地球
That's what we're going to do.
这就是我们要做的
Mr。Chekov，can we warp？
切科夫先生 我们能曲速飞行吗
Sir，if we go to warp，
长官 如果我们曲速飞行
we run the risk of seriously damaging the core！
曲速核心会严重损害的风险很大
Can we do it？
能不能飞
Technically，yes，
从技术层面上讲是可以的
but I would not advise it，Captain.
但我不建议这么做 舰长
Noted.
知道了
Mr。Sulu，set course for Earth.
苏鲁先生 设定去地球的航线
Yes，sir.
是 长官
Punch it.
启动
Well，at least we're moving again.
最起码我们又在移动了
If you think you're safe at warp，
如果你们觉得在曲速域是安全的
you're wrong.
那就错了
Lieutenant Uhura，contact Starfleet.
乌胡拉上尉 联系星际舰队
Tell them we were pursued into the Neutral Zone
说我们被一艘无标记的联邦星舰
by an unmarked Federation ship.
追赶到了中立区
Comms are down，sir.
通讯系统失灵了 长官
Permission to come on the bridge.
请求进入舰桥
Dr。Marcus.
马科斯博士
He's gonna catch up with us，and when he does，
他会赶上我们的 当他赶上了
the only thing that's gonna stop him destroying this ship is me，
只有我可以让他不摧毁这艘船
so you have to let me talk to him.
所以你得让我和他谈谈
Carol，we're at warp。He can't catch up with us.
卡罗尔 我们在曲速域 他追不上我们
Yes，he can。He's been developing a ship
不 他可以 他一直在研究一种
that has advanced warp capabilities…
有高级曲速飞行能力的星舰
Captain！I'm getting a reading I don't understand.
舰长 仪表的读数让我很不解
Where are we？
我们在哪
We're 237，000 kilometers from Earth.
离地球237000公里处
- Damage report！- Weapons are way down.
- 损坏报告 - 武器已失灵
Shields are dropping.
防护盾快撑不住了
We're defenseless，sir.
我们已无防御能力 长官
Sir，we have a bulkhead breach.
长官 有个舱壁缺口了
- Where's the damage？- Major hull damage，Captain.
- 缺口在哪里 - 主船体 舰长
Evasive maneuvers！Get us to Earth！Right now！
规避战术 带我们去地球 快
Captain！Stop！Everybody on this ship is going to die
舰长 停下 如果你不让我和他谈
if you don't let me speak to him.
这船上的每个人都会死
Uhura，hail him.
乌胡拉 呼叫他
Sir。It's me。It's Carol.
长官 是我 卡罗尔
What are you doing on that ship？
你在那艘船上做什么
I heard what you said.
我听到你说的了
That you made a mistake
你犯下了错误
and now you're doing everything you can to fix it.
现在正尽全力去弥补它
But，Dad，
但是 爸爸
I don't believe that the man who raised me
我不敢相信抚养我长大的人
is capable of destroying a ship full of innocent people.
会摧毁一艘满载无辜的人的星舰
And，if I'm wrong about that，
假如我错了
then you're gonna have to do it with me on board.
那您就连我一起杀了吧
Actually，Carol，I won't.
事实上 卡罗尔 我不会那么做的
- Jim… - Can we intercept the transport signal？
- 吉姆 - 我们能中断传送信号吗
No，sir.
不行 长官
Carol！
卡罗尔
Captain Kirk，without authorization
柯克舰长 你未经授权
and in league with the fugitive John Harrison，
与逃犯约翰·哈里森为伍
you went rogue in enemy territory，
肆意进入敌人的领地
leaving me no choice
我不得不追捕你
but to hunt you down and destroy you.
并摧毁你的星舰
Lock phasers.
相位炮准备
Wait，sir，wait，wait，wait！
等等 长官 等等
I'll make this quick.
我会速度解决你们
Target all aft torpedoes on the Enterprise bridge.
所有舰尾鱼雷瞄准进取号舰桥
Sir，my crew was just following my orders.
长官 我的船员都只是听命于我
I take full responsibility for my actions.
我对我的行为负全责
But they were mine and they were mine alone.
一切后果 只由我一个人承担
If I transmit Khan's location to you now，
我现在就将可汗的位置发送给您
all that I ask is that you spare them.
我只请求您能放过他们
Please，sir.
求您了 长官
I'll do anything you want.
我任您处置
Just let them live.
给他们留条生路
That's a hell of an apology.
真是感人的道歉
But if it's any consolation，
不过你也不必太内疚
I was never going to spare your crew.
因为我根本没打算放过你的船员
Fire when…
准备开火
I'm sorry.
我对不起大家
Our weapons won't fire，sir！
我们的武器无法开火 长官
Our shields are down！We're losing power！
我们的防护盾关闭了 能量不足
Someone in engineering just manually reset our systems！
有人在工程部手动重置了我们的系统
What do you mean，「Someone」？Who？
「有人」是什么意思 是谁
Their weapons have powered down。Sir.
他们的武器没电了 长官
Enterprise！Can you hear me？
进取号 能听到吗
Scotty！
小科
Guess what I found behind Jupiter.
猜猜我在木星后面发现了什么
- You're on that ship！- I snuck on.
- 你在那艘船上 - 我溜上来的
And seeing as I've just committed an act of treason
鉴于我刚刚犯下了背叛
against a Starfleet Admiral，
星际舰队上将的大罪
I'd really like to get off this bloody ship.
我巴不得早点离开这艘该死的船
Now beam me out！
快把我传送回去吧
You're a miracle worker.
你真是个奇迹
We're a little low on power right now.
我们现在能量不太够
Just stand by。Stand by.
留在那儿待命 待命
What do you mean，「Low on power」？
「能量不够」是什么意思
What happened to the Enterprise？
进取号怎么了
Call you back.
一会打给你
Scotty！
小科
Spock。Our ship，how is she？
斯波克 我们的星舰状况如何
Our options are limited，Captain.
我们的选择有限 舰长
We cannot fire and we cannot flee.
我们既不能开火也不能撤离
There is one option.
还有个选择
Uhura，when you get Scotty back，
乌胡拉 小科回电的时候
- patch him through。- Yes，sir.
- 把信号转接给我 - 是的 长官
Mr。Spock，you have the conn.
斯波克先生 你来操舵
Captain，I strongly object.
舰长 我强烈反对
To what？I haven't said anything yet.
反对什么 我什么都还没说
Since we cannot take the ship from the outside，
既然我们无法从外部攻击那艘星舰
the only way we can take it is from within.
唯一的办法就是从内部拿下
And as a large boarding party would be detected，
而大规模人员登船会被发现
it is optimal for you to take
所以最理想的策略是
as few members of the crew as possible.
带领尽可能少的人员
You will meet resistance，requiring personnel
你会遇到敌人 因此合适的人员
with advanced combat abilities
要具备高超作战能力
and innate knowledge of that ship.
还得对那艘船有足够的了解
This indicates that you plan to align with Khan，
这意味着你要和可汗 也就是
the very man we were sent here to destroy.
我们此行要消灭的人结盟
I'm not aligning with him，I'm using him.
我不是要与他结盟 我是在利用他
「The enemy of my enemy is my friend.」
敌人的敌人就是我的朋友
An Arabic proverb attributed to a prince who was
这是一句阿拉伯谚语 出自一个
betrayed and decapitated by his own subjects.
被自己的子民背叛并斩首的王子之口
Still，it's a hell of a quote.
但这句话很有用
I will go with you，Captain.
我要跟你一起去 舰长
No，I need you on the bridge.
不 你要留在舰桥上
I cannot allow you to do this.
我不允许你这么做
It is my function aboard this ship to advise you
我在船上的职责就是给你建议
on making the wisest decisions possible，
让你作出尽可能明智的决策
something I firmly believe
而我坚信
you are incapable of doing in this moment.
你此刻没有作出明智决策的能力
You're right！
没错
What I'm about to do，it doesn't make any sense，
我现在要做的事一点都不合理
it's not logical。It is a gut feeling.
不合逻辑 完全靠直觉
I have no idea what I'm supposed to do.
我不知道我该做什么
I only know what I can do.
我只知道我能做什么
The Enterprise and her crew need someone
进取号和她的船员需要
in that chair that knows what he's doing.
头脑清醒的人来主持大局
And it's not me.
而那个人不是我
It's you，Spock.
是你 斯波克
Tell me everything you know about that ship.
告诉我你所知道的关于那艘星舰的一切
Dreadnought class.
无畏级星舰
Two times the size，three times the speed.
两倍大小 三倍速度
Advanced weaponry。Modified for a minimal crew.
配备先进武器 所需船员数量极少
Unlike most Federation vessels，
它与其他联邦星舰不同
it's built solely for combat.
它是专为战斗而设计的
I will do everything I can
我会竭尽所能让你
to make you answer for what you did.
为所犯下的罪行付出代价
But right now I need your help.
但是现在我需要你的帮助
In exchange for what？
用什么来交换
You said you'd do anything for your crew.
你说过你愿意为了你的船员赴汤蹈火
- I can guarantee their safety。- Captain.
- 我能确保他们的安全 - 舰长
You can't even guarantee the safety of your own crew.
你连自己船员的安全都无法保证
Bones，what are you doing with that tribble？
老骨头 你为什么在鼓捣一只毛毛球
The tribble's dead.
这只毛毛球已经死了
I'm injecting Khan's platelets
我在将可汗的血小板
into the deceased tissue of a necrotic host.
注入到它已经坏死的组织中
Khan's cells regenerate like nothing I've ever seen，
我从没见过像可汗细胞这样的再生能力
and I want to know why.
我想知道为什么
You coming with me or not？
你到底跟不跟我一起去
You want to do what？
你想做什么
We're coming over there.
我们要过去
Sulu's maneuvering the Enterprise into position as we speak.
苏鲁正在将进取号开到理想位置
To this ship？How？
上这艘船吗 怎么上
There's a cargo door，
有个货舱门
hangar 7，access port 101A.
在7号机库 101A号入口
You need to find the manual override to open that airlock.
你需要找到手动阀来开启舱闸
Are you crazy？Whoever you are.
你疯了吗 你是谁来着
Just listen to him，Scotty。It's gonna be all right.
按他说的做 小科 没问题的
It is not gonna be all right.
没问题才怪
You want me to open an airlock into space，
你想让我在太空开启舱闸
whereupon I will freeze，die and explode！
我肯定得被冻死 然后粉身碎骨
Lieutenant，from our current position，
上尉 从我们现在的位置
is it possible to establish contact with New Vulcan？
能否联络上新瓦肯星
- I'll do my best。- Thank you.
- 我尽量试试 - 谢谢
Mr。Sulu，what is the status of the other ship？
苏鲁先生 另一艘星舰的情况怎么样
Their systems are still offline.
他们的系统仍然处于离线状态
I'm aligning our ship now.
我正在调整我们星舰的位置
Scotty，how we doing over there？
小科 那边情况如何
Captain，I wish I had better news.
舰长 我希望能有更好的消息
They've locked out access to the ship's computer.
但是这艘船的电脑的入口已经被关闭
They'll have full weapons in three minutes.
他们的武器3分钟后就会全部恢复正常
That means next time I won't be able to stop them
这意味着我无法再次阻止他们
destroying the Enterprise。Stand by.
摧毁进取号了 待命
Commander，our trash exhaust is aimed at
中校 我们的垃圾排放口已经瞄准了
access port 101A of the other ship.
对方星舰的101A号入口
Captain，the ships are aligned.
舰长 星舰已就位
Copy that.
收到
- Scotty！- I'm in the hangar.
- 小科 - 我已经在机库了
Give me a minute.
给我点时间
I'm running。Stand by.
我在跑 待命
Whoa，whoa，hold on，now，Captain.
等等 舰长
This door is very wee。I mean，you know，small.
这个舱门太小了 就那么一丁点大
It's four square meters，tops.
最多也就4平方米
It's gonna be like jumping out of a moving car，
就像想从在桥上飞奔的车里跳出去
off a bridge，into your shot glass.
然后落到桥下的一个烈酒杯里一样
It's okay。I've done it before.
没关系 这事我干过
Yeah，it was vertical.
当时我是垂直跳下去的
We jumped onto a… it was a…
我们跳到了一个 一个
It doesn't matter。Scotty…
这不重要 小科
Did you find the manual override？
你找到手动阀了吗
The manual override，Scotty.
手动阀 小科
Not yet，not yet.
还没 还没
Captain，before you launch，you should be aware there is
舰长 请你在出发前意识到
a considerable debris field between our ships.
两艘星舰之间会有相当多的残骸
Spock，not now.
斯波克 别说了
Scotty，you good？
小科 你那边好了吗
It's not easy！
没那么容易
Just give me two seconds，all right，you mad bastard！
别催我行吗 你这个疯子
Tell me this is gonna work.
跟我说这一定会成功
I have neither the information
我既没有真凭实据
nor the confidence to do so，Doctor.
也没有信心向你保证 医生
Okay，Captain，stand by.
舰长 马上搞定
Boy，you're a real comfort.
你可真会安慰人
Come on，come on，come on.
快点 快点
Yes！
搞定
Okay，okay！I'm set to open the door.
行了 我随时可以把门打开
You ready？
准备好了吗
Are you？
你呢
Spock，pull the trigger.
斯波克 把我们弹出去
Yes，Captain.
是的 舰长
Launching activation sequence on
运行激活程序倒计时
three，
三
two，
二
one.
一
Sir，Kirk is headed for collision at .432！
长官 柯克在0.432方向有障碍物
Captain，there is debris directly ahead.
舰长 你正前方有残骸
Copy that.
收到
Whoa！Jim，you're way off course！
吉姆 你偏离轨道了
I know，I know！I can see that.
我知道 我看出来了
Don't move.
不许动
Use your display compass，Captain.
用你的可视指南针 舰长
You must correct precisely
你必须精确调整
- 37.243 degrees。- Got it.
- 37.243度 - 知道了
I'm working my way back.
我正在想办法重返轨道
（偏离轨道）
Scotty，you're gonna be ready with that door，right？
小科 你准备好开门了吧
What are you doing in here？
你在这儿干嘛
Wee bit of maintenance on the airlock console。You're big.
我在维修舱闸控制台 你块头真大
Mr。Scott，where are you？
斯科特先生 你在哪儿
Captain，he can't seem to hear you.
舰长 他好像听不到你说话
I'm working on getting his signal back。Stand by.
我正在重获他的信号 待命
- Damn it。- Captain，what is it？
- 见鬼 - 舰长 怎么了
My helmet was hit.
我的头盔被击中了
Uhura，tell me you have Mr。Scott back.
乌胡拉 联系上斯科特了吗
Not yet。I'm still working on a signal.
还没 我还在搜索信号
His communicator is working.
他的通讯工具无故障
I don't know why he isn't responding.
我不知道他为什么不回答
What is that？
那是什么
Are you Starfleet or private security？
你是星际舰队的还是私人保镖
Show me your other hand.
让我看看你另一只手
Because you look like private security.
你看起来像私人保镖
Imminent collision detected！
前方有障碍
Khan，use evasive action！
可汗 注意躲避
- There is debris directly ahead。- I see it.
- 正前方有残骸 - 看到了
Mr。Sulu，did we lose Khan？
苏鲁先生 与可汗失去联系了吗
I don't know，Commander.
不知道 中校
I'm having trouble tracking him in all this debris.
很难在这些残骸中追踪到他
Was Khan hit？
可汗被击中了吗
We are trying to find him now.
我们正在找他
Captain，you need to adjust your target destination
舰长 你需要调整目标方向
to 183 by 473 degrees.
至183/473度
Spock，my display's dead.
斯波克 我的显示屏坏了
I'm flying blind.
航线没了
Captain，without your display compass，
舰长 没有可视指南针
hitting your target destination is mathematically impossible.
要到达目标是不可能的
Spock，if I get back，
斯波克 如果我能回去
we really need to talk about your bedside manner.
我必须好好教教你该怎么说话
Commander，he's not going to make it.
中校 他到不了
My display is still functioning.
我的显示屏没坏
I see you，Kirk，
我看到你了 柯克
you're 200 meters ahead of me
你在我前方200米
at my one o'clock.
1点钟方向处
Come to your left a few degrees and follow me.
你往左调整几度 跟着我
Scotty，we're getting close.
小科 我们马上就到了
We need a warm welcome.
你要好好迎接我们啊
Do you copy？Do you copy？Scotty？
收到了吗 收到了吗 小科
If you can hear us，Mr。Scott，
如果听到的话 斯科特先生
open the door in ten，nine，
请在倒计时结束前打开舱门 十 九
Scotty！
小科
That person counting down，
那人在倒计时
- what is that？- eight，
- 怎么回事 - 八
I think you're hearing things，mate.
你肯定是幻听了 伙计
- Seven。- Mr。Scott，where are you？
- 七 - 斯科特先生 你在哪儿
Six，five
六 五
1，800 meters。1，600 meters.
1800米 1600米
- Scotty，where are you？- three
- 小科 你在哪儿 - 三
Do you copy，Scotty？Please！
收到了吗 小科 求你了
Two.
二
- Sorry about this。- About what？
- 对不起 - 什么对不起
- Mr。Scott，open the door！- Open the door！
- 斯科特先生 快开门 - 开门
Mr。Scott，now！
斯科特 快
Welcome aboard.
欢迎登舰
- It's good to see you，Scotty。- Who is that？
- 见到你真好 小科 - 他是谁
Khan，Scotty.
可汗 这是小科
Scotty，Khan.
小科 这是可汗
Hello.
你好
They'll know we're here.
他们很快就会发现我们
I know the best way to the bridge.
我知道到达舰桥的最佳路线
It's locked to stun.
这枪设定在眩晕模式
Theirs won't be.
敌人可不会这么仁慈
Try not to get shot.
尽量别被击中
Commander，I have that transmission as requested.
中校 已经联系上新瓦肯星
On screen，please.
请在大屏幕上显示出来
Stand by.
准备
Mr。Spock.
斯波克先生
Admiral.
上将
I'll deal with you in a…
我等会儿再处理你
I am ashamed to be your daughter.
作为你的女儿我感到很羞耻
Sir，we just had a hangar door open
长官 第13层的机库门
on deck 13.
刚刚被打开过
Khan.
可汗
They're going to have full power
他们马上就恢复电力了
and we're walking？
而我们居然还用走的？
The turbolifts are easily tracked
高速电梯很容易被追踪
and Marcus would have us in a cage.
被马科斯发现就死定了
This path runs adjacent to the engine room.
这条路在轮机舱附近
They know they won't be able to use their weapons here
他们很清楚在这里使用武器
without destabilizing the warp core，
会影响到曲速核
which gives us the advantage.
这就是我们的优势
- Where'd you find this guy？- It's a long story.
- 这家伙你从哪儿找来的 - 说来话长
I will be brief.
我长话短说
In your travels，
你在旅程中
did you ever encounter a man named Khan？
有没有遇到过一个叫可汗的人
As you know，
你也知道
I have made a vow never to give you information
我发过誓 不会向你透露任何
that could potentially alter your destiny.
可能会改变你命运的信息
Your path is yours to walk，and yours alone.
你自己的路要你自己去走 没人能干涉
That being said，
话虽如此
Khan Noonien Singh is the most dangerous adversary
但可汗·努尼恩·辛格是进取号遇到过的
the Enterprise ever faced.
对手中最危险的一个
He is brilliant，ruthless，
他聪明过人 冷酷无情
and he will not hesitate to kill
而且他视你们的性命
every single one of you.
为蝼蚁
Did you defeat him？
你打败他了吗
At great cost。Yes.
是的 不过付出了极大的代价
How？
如何做到的
I don't mean to tempt fate here，but where is everybody？
我不是活得不耐烦 但他们人呢
The ship is designed to be flown by minimal crew，
这艘星舰所需的船员极少
one，if necessary.
如果必要的话 一个人也行
One？I…
一个就够了吗
- You all right？- Yeah。Where's Khan？
- 你没事吧 - 可汗在哪儿
Lieutenant，I need you to assemble all senior medical
上尉 请你召集医疗部和工程部的
and engineering staff in the weapons bay.
所有高级人员到武器舱
All right.
好的
Dr。McCoy，you inadvertently activated a torpedo.
麦科伊医生 你之前无意中启动过鱼雷
Could you replicate the process？
你能重复这个过程吗
Why the hell would I want to do that？
我为什么要这么做
Can you or can you not？
能还是不能
Damn it，man，I'm a doctor，
见鬼 伙计 我是个医生
not a torpedo technician！
不是鱼雷技师
The fact that you are a doctor is precisely
正因为你是个医生
why I need you to listen very carefully.
所以你更应该仔细听清我说的活
Where is he？
他在哪儿
Shit！
他妈的
This way.
这边走
The minute we get to the bridge，drop him.
我们一到舰桥 就把他放倒
What，stun him？Khan？I thought he was helping us.
要击晕可汗吗 我还以为他在帮我们
I'm pretty sure we're helping him.
我很肯定是我们在帮他
Power coming online，sir！
电力恢复正常 长官
- Retarget the Enterprise now。- Aye，sir.
- 现在重新瞄准进取号 - 是 长官
Make sure he stays down.
盯着他 别让他跑了
- Excuse me。- Yeah.
- 借过 - 好
Admiral Marcus，you're under arrest.
马科斯上将 你被捕了
You're not actually going to do this，are you？
你不会真打算这样做吧
Admiral，get out of the chair.
上将 离开这椅子
You better stop and think about what you're doing，Kirk.
你最好想清楚自己在干什么 柯克
You better think about what you did on Kronos.
想想你在克隆那斯都干了什么
You made an incursion onto an enemy planet！
你入侵了敌方的星球
You killed a Klingon patrol.
还杀死了克林贡人的一支巡逻队
Even if you got away without a trace，war is coming.
就算你能全身而退 战争也在所难免
And who is going to lead us？You？
谁来指挥 你吗
If I'm not in charge，
要是没我指挥
our entire way of life is decimated！
我们就彻底完蛋了
So you want me off this ship，
要我离开这艘星舰
you better kill me.
还不如杀了我
I'm not going to kill you，sir.
我不打算杀你 长官
But I could stun your ass and drag you out of that chair.
但我可以把你电晕后从那椅子上拖下来
I'd rather not do that in front of your daughter.
我不希望在你女儿面前这样做
- You all right？- Yes，Captain.
- 你还好吗 - 没事 舰长
Jim！
吉姆
Listen！Wait！
听我说 等等
You…
你
You should have let me sleep.
你应该让我沉睡下去
Where is the Captain，Mr。Sulu？
舰长在哪 苏鲁先生
Our sensor array's down，sir。I can't find him.
我们的传感器阵列坏了 找不到他
I'm going to make this very simple for you.
我把话说得简单一些
- Captain。- Your crew for my crew.
- 舰长 - 用我的船员换你的船员
You betrayed us.
你背叛了我们
You are smart，Mr。Spock.
你很聪明 斯波克先生
Spock don't…
斯波克 不要…
Mr。Spock，give me my crew.
斯波克先生 把我的船员还给我
And what will you do when you get them？
还你以后你打算怎么做
Continue the work we were doing before we were banished.
继续我们被流放前的任务
Which，as I understand it，
照我的理解
involves the mass genocide of any being you find
这项任务包括灭绝所有
to be less than superior.
你认为比你劣等的种族
Shall I destroy you，Mr。Spock？
斯波克先生 是要我消灭你呢
Or will you give me what I want？
还是你乖乖地把我想要的交给我
We have no transporter capabilities.
我们没有传送能力
Fortunately mine are perfectly functional.
刚好我的星舰功能齐全
Drop your shields.
放下防护盾
If I do so，
我要是照做的话
I have no guarantee that you will not destroy the Enterprise.
难保你不会消灭进取号
Well，let's play this out logically then，Mr。Spock.
斯波克先生 我来帮你搞清楚状况
Firstly，I will kill your Captain
首先 我会杀了你们的舰长
to demonstrate my resolve.
以示我的决心
Then if yours holds，I will have no choice
如果你们还是不合作 我就只好
but to kill you and your entire crew.
杀掉你和你的所有船员
If you destroy our ship，
要是你毁了我们的船
you will also destroy your own people.
你的同伴也难逃一死
Your crew requires oxygen to survive，mine does not.
你的船员需要氧气活命 我的不需要
I will target your life support systems
我会攻击你们位于舰尾
located behind the aft nacelle.
引擎舱后的维生系统
And after every single person aboard your ship suffocates，
等到你们船上每个人都窒息身亡
I will walk over your cold corpses to recover my people.
我再踏过你们冰冷的尸体去营救我的同伴
Now，
现在
shall we begin？
我们可以开始了吗
Lower shields.
放下防护盾
A wise choice，Mr。Spock.
明智的选择 斯波克先生
I see your 72 torpedoes are still in their tubes.
我看到那72枚鱼雷还在冷冻管内
If they are not mine，Commander，
如果你敢偷梁换柱 中校
I will know it.
我会知道的
Vulcans do not lie.
瓦肯人从不说谎
The torpedoes are yours.
这些鱼雷都是你的
Thank you，Mr。Spock.
谢谢 斯波克先生
I have fulfilled your terms.
我已经满足了你的要求
Now fulfill mine.
现在换你了
Well，Kirk，it seems apt to return you to your crew.
柯克 还是让你和你的船员团聚吧
After all，
毕竟
no ship should go down without her captain.
舰长就该跟他的星舰一起命丧黄泉
He's locking phasers on us，sir！
他在用相位炮瞄准我们 长官
Let us out of here now！
快让我们出来
Shields at 6%！
防护盾防御能力只剩6%
The torpedoes！How much time，Lieutenant？
鱼雷 还剩多少时间 上尉
Twelve seconds，sir！
12秒 长官
Crew of the Enterprise，
进取号的船员们
prepare for imminent proximity detonation.
近距离爆炸冲击即将发生 请准备
What's he talking about？What detonation？
他在说什么 什么爆炸
The torpedoes。He armed the damn torpedoes！
鱼雷 他启动了那些该死的鱼雷
No！
不
Sir，their weapons have been knocked out.
长官 他们的武器已被摧毁
- Not bad，Commander。- Thank you，Lieutenant.
- 干得好 中校 - 多谢 上尉
- Bones！- Bones！
- 老骨头 - 老骨头
- Nurse！- I got you。I got you.
- 护士 - 来了 我来扶你
Dr。Marcus.
马科斯博士
Good to see you，Jim.
很高兴见到你 吉姆
You helped Spock detonate those torpedoes？
你帮斯波克引爆了那些鱼雷吗
Damn right I did.
一点没错
He killed Khan's crew！
他居然杀了可汗的船员
Spock's cold，but he's not that cold.
斯波克是很冷血 但还不至于做这种事
I've got Khan's crew.
可汗的船员在我这里
Seventy- two human popsicles，
72条人体冰棍
safe and sound in their cryo tubes.
安然无恙地躺在冷冻管里
Son of a bitch！
你这小子
Sir，the central power grid is failing！
长官 中心电力网不行了
- Switch to auxiliary power。- Auxiliary power failing，sir.
- 调用后备电源 - 后备电源也不行了
Commander，our ship's caught in Earth's gravity！
中校 星舰被地球的引力吸住了
- Can we stop？- I can't do anything.
- 能停下吗 - 不行
Sorry！Oh，no.
对不起 不
Clear the area！
赶紧疏散
Engage emergency lockdown！I hope you don't get seasick.
进入紧急戒备状态 希望你不会晕船
- Do you？- Yeah.
- 你会吗 - 会
Lieutenant，sound evacuation，all decks.
上尉 通知各个甲板的人员撤离
Aye，sir.
是的 长官
As acting Captain，
我以代理舰长的身份
I order you to abandon this ship.
命令你们弃舰
I will remain behind and divert all power
我会留下来 将所有能量
to life support and evacuation shuttle bays.
提供给维生系统和逃生穿梭机舱
Evacuation protocols…
撤离方案…
I order you to abandon the ship！
我命令你们弃船
All due respect，Commander，but we're not going anywhere.
恕我直言 中校 我们是不会走的
One day I've been off this ship！One bloody day！
我才离开这艘船一天 他妈才一天
Gravity systems are failing。Hold on！Hold on！
重力系统正在失灵 撑住 撑住
Attention，all decks.
各甲板请注意
Evacuation protocols initiated.
撤离方案现已生效
Proceed to exit bays and report to your assigned shuttle.
请前往出口 到指定的穿梭机处报到
There won't be time for evacuation
如果我们没有足够能量稳住这艘船
if we don't get power to stabilize the damn ship！
那根本就不够时间撤离
- Can we restore it？- Only from engineering.
- 可以修好吗 - 只能在工程部修
We have to get back to the warp core.
我们得回到曲速核那里
Jim？
吉姆
Scotty，we got to get the power back on！
小科 我们得让星舰恢复动力
Come on！
快点
- Scotty，we got to jump！- What？
- 小科 我们得跳过去 - 什么
Jump！Jump！
跳啊 跳啊
Oh，God.
我的天
Emergency power at 15% and dropping.
应急电源还剩15% 仍在降低
Attention，all decks.
各甲板请注意
Evacuation protocols initiated.
撤离方案现已生效
Proceed to exit bays and report to your assigned shuttle.
请前往出口 到指定的穿梭机处报到
- Jim？- Hold on！
- 吉姆 - 坚持住
I can't.
我不行了
I've got you，Captain！
我抓住你了 舰长
- Chekov。- Don't let go！
- 切科夫 - 别放手
Even if we get the warp core online，
即使重启了曲速核
we've still got to redirect the power！
我们还要将能量重定向
- He's right，Captain！- What are you talking about？
- 他说得对 舰长 - 你们在说什么
Someone has to hit the manual override.
必须有人去打开手动开关
Laddie，there's a switch…
小伙子 有个开关…
Behind the deflector dish！I'll flip the switch！
就在碟形偏转器后边 我去扳开关
Let's go！
走吧
Oh，no.
不
Evacuation protocols initiated.
撤离方案现已生效
Proceed to exit bays and report to your assigned shuttle.
请前往出口 到指定的穿梭机处报到
Mr。Sulu，divert any remaining power to stabilizers.
苏鲁先生 把剩余电力都调去稳定器
Doing what I can，sir。Doing what I can.
尽我所能 长官 尽我所能
Core misaligned。Danger.
核心偏离 危险
- Oh，no，no，no，no！- What？
- 不 不 不 - 怎么了
The housings are misaligned！
底座的方向偏离了
There's no way we can redirect the power！
我们无法将能量重定向
The ship's dead，sir。She's gone.
这艘船死定了 长官 她没救了
- No，she's not。- Wait，Jim！
- 不 她还有救 - 等等 吉姆
If we go in there，we'll die！
进去的话会死的
Do you hear me？The radiation will kill us！
听见没 辐射会要了我们的命
Will you listen to me？What the hell are you doing？
你有在听吗 你他妈的在干嘛
I'm opening the door。I'm going in.
我在开门 我要进去
That door is there to stop us from getting irradiated！
这扇门是用来防辐射的
We'd be dead before we made the climb！
没来得及爬上去我们就死了
You're not making the climb.
不用你爬
Danger。Core misaligned.
危险 核心偏离
If we don't get power or shields back online，
如果不能重获动力或者重启防护盾
we're gonna be incinerated on re- entry！
我们进入大气层时就会被烧成灰
Warp core is back online！
曲速核已恢复运作
Maximum thrusters，Mr。Sulu！
最大推力 苏鲁先生
Thrusters at maximum！Stand by！Stand by！
最大推力 准备 准备
Shields restored！
防护盾已修复
Commander，power online.
中校 动力已恢复
Mr。Spock，altitude stabilizing.
斯波克先生 正在稳定飞行高度
It's a miracle.
这是个奇迹
There are no such things.
没有奇迹这回事
Engineering to bridge.
工程部呼叫舰桥
- Mr。Spock！- Mr。Scott.
- 斯波克先生 - 斯科特先生
Sir，you'd better get down here.
长官 你最好下来看看
Better hurry.
越快越好
Open it.
开门
The decontamination process is not complete.
净化处理还没完成
You'd flood the whole compartment.
开门的话 辐射会溢满整个舱
The door's locked，sir.
门锁住了 长官
How's our ship？
我们的船怎样了
Out of danger.
已脱离危险
You saved the crew.
你救了所有船员
You used what he wanted against him.
你利用他想要的东西来攻击他
That's a nice move.
这招真妙
It is what you would have done.
换了你也会那样做
And this，
这招
this is what you would have done.
这招只有你想得出来
It was only logical.
靠的是逻辑
I'm scared，Spock.
我好害怕 斯波克
Help me not be.
让我不要害怕
How do you choose not to feel？
你是怎么摒弃自己的感情的
I do not know.
我不知道
Right now I am failing.
我现在做不到了
I want you to know why I couldn't let you die.
我想让你知道 为什么我不能让你去死
Why I went back for you.
为什么我回去救你
Because you are my friend.
因为你是我的朋友
Khan！
可汗
God，that was close！
天啊 差点就撞上了
Set destination，Starfleet Headquarters！
设定目的地 星际舰队总部
Engines compromised.
发动机受损
Cannot guarantee destination.
不能保证到达目的地
Confirm order.
请确认命令
Confirm.
确认
Search the enemy ship for signs of life.
探测敌舰是否存在生命迹象
Sir，there's no way anyone survived.
长官 不可能有人活下来
He could.
他能
Yes，sir.
是的 长官
Whoa！He just jumped 30 meters！
他刚往下跳了30米
Can we beam him up？
能把他传送上来吗
There's too much damage.
星舰受损太严重
I have no incoming signal.
收不到信号
But it may be possible to beam you down，sir.
不过也许能将你传送下去 长官
Go get him.
去抓住他
- Stand by for coordinates。- Yes，sir.
- 准备好坐标 - 是的 长官
Enter 3517 by 2598.
输入坐标（3517，2598）
Coordinates confirmed.
坐标已确认
Get me a cryo tube，now！
给我搬一个冷冻管过来 快
Get this guy out of the cryo tube.
把这人抬出冷冻管
Keep him in an induced coma.
让他保持诱导昏迷状态
We're gonna put Kirk inside.
我们要把柯克放进去
It's our only chance to preserve his brain function.
这是唯一可能保住他大脑机能的方法
How much of Khan's blood is left？
可汗的血还剩多少
None.
没了
Enterprise to Spock。Spock！
进取号呼叫斯波克 斯波克
Activate the cryogenic sequence.
运行冷冻程序
McCoy to bridge.
麦科伊呼叫舰桥
I can't reach Spock。I need Khan alive.
我联系不上斯波克 要活捉可汗
You get that son of a bitch back on board right now！
马上把那狗娘养的弄到船上
I think he can save Kirk.
他应该能救柯克
Can we beam them up to the ship？
能把他们传送到船上吗
They keep moving！I can't get a lock on either of them.
他们不停在动 我一个都无法锁定
Can you beam someone down？
能传送其他人下去吗
Spock！
斯波克
Spock，stop！Stop！
斯波克 住手 快住手
He's our only chance to save Kirk！
只有他能救柯克
- What is it？- It's a boy.
- 男孩女孩？- 男孩
Let's call him Jim.
就叫吉姆吧
Your father was captain of a starship for 12 minutes.
你父亲当过12分钟的星舰舰长
He saved 800 lives。I dare you to do better.
他救了800人 你一定会做得更好
Don't be so melodramatic。You were barely dead.
别太激动 你死不了
It was the transfusion that really took its toll.
输血的副作用真大
You were out cold for two weeks.
你已经昏迷两周了
Transfusion？
输血？
Your cells were heavily irradiated。We had no choice.
你的细胞受到严重辐射 我们别无他法
Khan？
可汗呢
Once we caught him，
一抓到他
I synthesized a serum from his superblood.
我就从他的超级血液中合成了一种血清
Tell me，are you feeling homicidal？
告诉我 你有没有想杀人的冲动
Power mad？Despotic？
或者变得迷恋权力 暴戾
No more than usual.
我很正常
How'd you catch him？
你是怎么抓住他的
I didn't.
不是我抓住他的
You saved my life.
你救了我的命
Uhura and I had something to do with it，too，you know.
其实乌胡拉和我也帮了忙
You saved my life，Captain。And the lives…
舰长 是你救了我和其他人…
Spock，just…
斯波克 少说两句吧
Thank you.
谢谢
You are welcome，Jim.
不客气 吉姆
There will always be those who mean to do us harm.
想要伤害我们的人一直存在
To stop them，
为了阻止他们
we risk awakening the same evil within ourselves.
我们不惜唤醒心中的恶魔
Our first instinct is to seek revenge
当我们所爱之人被夺走时
when those we love are taken from us.
我们最初想到的会是报复
But that's not who we are.
但我们并不是这样的人
We are here today
我们今天在此
to rechristen the U.S.S。Enterprise，
举行联邦星舰进取号的重命名仪式
and to honor those who lost their lives nearly one year ago.
并向约一年前牺牲的英雄们致敬
When Christopher Pike first gave me his ship，
克里斯托弗·派克把他的星舰交给我的同时
he had me recite the Captain's Oath，
让我把舰长的誓词背下来
words I didn't appreciate at the time.
当时我并不领会个中含义
Now I see them as a call for us to remember
如今我觉得 它是在提醒我们
who we once were，
要牢记历史
and who we must be again.
并再创辉煌
And those words？
誓词是这样写的
Space，the final frontier.
宇宙 人类最后的边疆
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
这些旅程属于星舰进取号
Her five- year mission，
她的下一个五年任务
to explore strange new worlds，
是去探索未知的新世界
to seek out new life and new civilizations，
找寻新的生命和新的文明
to boldly go where no one has gone before.
勇敢地航向前人所未至的领域
Captain on the bridge.
舰长到达舰桥
It's hard to get out of it once you've had a taste，
一旦坐上去就不想下来了
isn't that right，Mr。Sulu？
是吧 苏鲁先生
「Captain」 does have a nice ring to it.
舰长这个头衔的确很风光
Chair's all yours，sir.
椅子物归原主 长官
Mr。Scott.
斯科特先生
How's our core？
曲速核情况如何
Purring like a kitten，Captain.
睡得正香 舰长
She's ready for a long journey.
她已作好踏上漫长旅程的准备
Excellent.
很好
Come on，Bones！It's gonna be fun.
别这样 老骨头 会很有趣的
Five years in space。God help me.
在太空待五年 神啊救救我吧
Dr。Marcus.
马科斯博士
I'm glad you could be a part of the family.
很高兴你能加入我们这个大家庭
It's nice to have a family.
有家的感觉真好
Spock.
斯波克
Captain.
舰长
Where shall we go？
我们该去哪
As a mission of this duration has never been attempted，
鉴于如此长时间的任务史无前例
I defer to your good judgment，Captain.
我相信你能作出正确的判断 舰长
Mr。Sulu，take us out.
苏鲁先生 我们出发吧
Aye，Captain.
是 舰长